<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
    <channel>
        <title>Blockchain on Redcell Talent Accelerator</title>
        <link>https://redcelltalent.com/tags/blockchain/</link>
        <description>Recent content in Blockchain on
            Redcell Talent Accelerator
        </description>
        <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
        <language>en-us</language>
        <copyright>Redcell, Pittsburgh, PA</copyright>
        <lastBuildDate>
            Tue, 20 Mar 2018 00:00:00 +0000
        </lastBuildDate>
        <atom:link href="/tags/blockchain/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/>
        
        <item>
            <title>Blockchain is about to transform the talent market and HR .</title>
            <link>https://redcelltalent.com/blog/talent-blockchain/</link>
            <pubDate>
                Tue, 20 Mar 2018 00:00:00 +0000
            </pubDate>
            
            <guid>https://redcelltalent.com/blog/talent-blockchain/</guid>
            <description>
                


&lt;h2 id=&#34;the-talent-blockchain-is-real-and-coming-soon&#34;&gt;The talent blockchain is real and coming soon&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Over the past few months, we have shared a number of indepth conversations with talent leaders, HR leaders and CEOs around the topic and state of recruitment in 2018 and beyond.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A question I&amp;rsquo;ve posed to all of them is the same I pose to you: &lt;i&gt;How much money and time is wasted on running background checks?&lt;/i&gt; How is that investment paying off for you?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In a recent Career Builder Survey of 2,500 HR Professionals, 56% of all HR managers had caught people lying on their resumes &amp;hellip; after they were hired.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It&amp;rsquo;s a fair question. Do you ever wonder how many hours are spent in verifying the credentials of candidates – many of whom have already been employed and have previously been vetted? While no one has an accurate figure, hundreds – even thousands – of hours per year are wasted in firms with even moderate hiring volume. And this doesn&amp;rsquo;t account for the actual expenses involved in running credit checks, criminal backgrounds, requesting transcripts&amp;hellip;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;What is you have an itinerant or seasonal workforce. Do you have to re-check them every few months? Generally speaking the answer is yes.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;What if there were a way to eliminate the need for constant re-verification? Would it be valuable to quickly know with certainty that the skills, qualifications, and experience the candidate lists are what they actually have?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;embellishment-works-both-ways&#34;&gt;Embellishment works both ways&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Let&amp;rsquo;s take this a step deeper. In that same survey, 62% found candidates embellishing skills or abilities. But like you, I&amp;rsquo;ve been on the other side of the coin &amp;hellip; writing job descriptions &amp;hellip;that only a true &amp;ldquo;unicorn&amp;rdquo; candidate could meet. Let&amp;rsquo;s call this job description &amp;ldquo;inflation.&amp;rdquo; While I haven&amp;rsquo;t done the research, I would be very surprised if there were no correlation between resume embellishment and job description inflation.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In the end. No one wins. and worse &amp;hellip; we&amp;rsquo;ve created an entire economic system that lacks any credibility or trust.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;the-gig-economy-is-making-things-worse&#34;&gt;The gig economy is making things worse&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As we move into the gig economy, new issues arise making it even harder to verify worker claims. Workers may have many different assignments and may develop a variety of skills and experiences that are hard to document and verify. They may have also taken self-learning or online programs and through those have gained new skills and abilities &amp;hellip; but without the &amp;ldquo;verification&amp;rdquo; of a known entity. As the contingent workforce expands, the task of verifying credentials and experience becomes more difficult.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It all comes back to trust. When we set requirements for a job &amp;hellip; let&amp;rsquo;s say a bachelors degree &amp;hellip; does the job require a bachelor&amp;rsquo;s degree? Is that a requirment to cut down the number of applicants &amp;hellip; does the actual classes and grades matter? How about the institution awarding the degree? What if the degree was attained 15 years ago?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So &amp;hellip; not only do we fundamentally not trust what is on a resume &amp;hellip; do we really even care enough or have time enough to look beyond the surface? And yet &amp;hellip; we spend time and money to run a perfunctory background check &amp;hellip;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;what-if-we-ran-the-numbers&#34;&gt;What if we ran the numbers?&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Let&amp;rsquo;s look at some numbers. The &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.bls.gov/news.release/jolts.nr0.htm&#34;&gt;BLS Job Openings and Labor Turnover Report&lt;/a&gt; recently published (March 16) indicating that January 2018 saw 5.6 million hires in the US.  The average background check runs anywhere from $30 to $300 per candidate. If firms only checked the individuals hired &amp;hellip; that could amount to as much as $1.6 Billion spent by US firms in January.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But Background checks have come a long way from the simplistic verification of ID and criminal history with spot checking of employment and educaiton.  Pre-employment checks have become so common that the federal government began to enforce &amp;ldquo;ban-the-box&amp;rdquo; regulations and laws. 43% of the contingent workforce is now checked at to the same degree as full time employees. Continuous screening is on the rise, and social media screening is growing at a rapid rate. As new screening tools develop, new regulations are sure to follow to more closely regulate for bias.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And because none of this information is shared or vetted between companies &amp;hellip; the duplication of costs is staggering.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;can-blockchain-help&#34;&gt;Can Blockchain help?&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The blockchain is best known as the platform for buying and selling Bitcoins. It was developed for that purpose and has a short history of securing financial transactions. But it is also being used in other areas ranging from the logistics to HR. It is one of the ways being explored to verify credentials such as education, previous employment, skills, and other data frequently required by employers. Blockchain could eliminate resume fraud and increase the integrity of the recruiting process because it is inherently secure.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A blockchain is an encrypted digital ledger of records that are organized into groups of data called blocks and distributed over a network. The blocks are located on servers called nodes linked together, hence the term “chain.” In effect, Blockchain is a way of decentralizing and sharing information across a network.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Whenever a new transaction occurs, the blockchain is authenticated across this network, before the transaction can be included in the next block on the chain. So, the agreement of each node is required to add the block into the chain. Only certain entities such as a specific person or corporation, have a digital ID and can add specific types of information (your college grades and degree, for example). Each node on the network has the same information, and all nodes must agree.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The blockchain creates trust because a copy of the chain showing every transaction is held by the entire network. If someone tries to cheat the system, they can be identified. The data in a block cannot be changed or deleted only added to and if anyone were to attempt to make a false entry, the other nodes would not allow it and the false data would be rejected.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A personal ID from a blockchain is totally secure and can be used in lots of ways from signing legal documents to verifying employment or experience.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;numerous-other-benefits-of-blockchain-for-recruitment-and-hr&#34;&gt;Numerous other benefits of blockchain for recruitment and HR&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A foundational talent blockchain could provide numerous additional benefits &amp;hellip; trusted data sets would lead to improved AI matching opportunities. Smart Contracts, which are a fundamental part of the blockchain infrastructure could automate and trigger a number of actions - such as HRIS enrollment, payment start and end dates, establish new contract-based employment, eliminate repetitive processes and increase speed. Automated compliance and transparency is another perk for modern firms and government regulators.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Better yet &amp;hellip; the talent blockchain is already here. Redcell Talent has been working with partners on the design of a state-of-the-art blockchain solution that will launch in the coming months. We&amp;rsquo;ve set up a visual demo that helps to demonstrate some of the uses and invite you to check it out!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you are interested in learning more about the Talent Blockchain and how Redcell Talent can assist you and your organization in getting up to speed with the revolution in talent technology ,be sure to connect with us!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In the mean time &amp;hellip; &lt;a href=&#34;http://blockchain.redcell.ai&#34;&gt;CHECK OUT THE TALENT BLOCKCHAIN DEMO&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;


&lt;p class=&#34;center&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;a href=&#34;https://indd.adobe.com/view/616532ee-70ec-40d7-9f31-208274561e1d&#34; class=&#34;button __download-link&#34;&gt;Download&lt;/a&gt;

  &amp;nbsp;
  &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/getinsomnia/insomnia/releases/vtalent-blockchain&#34;
     class=&#34;button button--no-outline&#34;
     target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;
    View on GitHub
  &lt;/a&gt;
  
&lt;/p&gt;








            </description>
        </item>
        
    </channel>
</rss>
