<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
    <channel>
        <title>Redcell Talent Accelerator on Redcell Talent Accelerator</title>
        <link>https://redcelltalent.com/</link>
        <description>Recent content in Redcell Talent Accelerator on
            Redcell Talent Accelerator
        </description>
        <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
        <language>en-us</language>
        <copyright>Redcell, Pittsburgh, PA</copyright>
        <lastBuildDate>
            Wed, 21 Mar 2018 00:00:00 +0000
        </lastBuildDate>
        <atom:link href="/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/>
        
        <item>
            <title>Blockchain is about to transform the talent market and HR .</title>
            <link>https://redcelltalent.com/blog/talent-blockchain/</link>
            <pubDate>
                Wed, 21 Mar 2018 00:00:00 +0000
            </pubDate>
            
            <guid>https://redcelltalent.com/blog/talent-blockchain/</guid>
            <description>
                


&lt;p&gt;&lt;meta property=&#34;og:image&#34; content=&#34;https://res.cloudinary.com/victorydev/image/upload/v1521645607/blockchain_img_vcqu2h.jpg&#34;&gt;
&lt;p align=&#34;center&#34;&gt;
  &lt;img src=&#34;https://res.cloudinary.com/victorydev/image/upload/v1521645607/blockchain_img_vcqu2h.jpg&#34; width=100% title=&#34;Github Logo&#34;&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;the-talent-blockchain-is-real-and-coming-soon&#34;&gt;The talent blockchain is real and coming soon&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Over the past few months, we have shared a number of indepth conversations with talent leaders, HR leaders and CEOs around the topic and state of recruitment in 2018 and beyond.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A question I&amp;rsquo;ve posed to all of them is the same I pose to you: &lt;i&gt;How much money and time is wasted on running background checks?&lt;/i&gt; How is that investment paying off for you?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In a recent Career Builder Survey of 2,500 HR Professionals, 56% of all HR managers had caught people lying on their resumes &amp;hellip; after they were hired.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It&amp;rsquo;s a fair question. Do you ever wonder how many hours are spent in verifying the credentials of candidates – many of whom have already been employed and have previously been vetted? While no one has an accurate figure, hundreds – even thousands – of hours per year are wasted in firms with even moderate hiring volume. And this doesn&amp;rsquo;t account for the actual expenses involved in running credit checks, criminal backgrounds, requesting transcripts&amp;hellip;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;What is you have an itinerant or seasonal workforce. Do you have to re-check them every few months? Generally speaking the answer is yes.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;What if there were a way to eliminate the need for constant re-verification? Would it be valuable to quickly know with certainty that the skills, qualifications, and experience the candidate lists are what they actually have?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;embellishment-works-both-ways&#34;&gt;Embellishment works both ways&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Let&amp;rsquo;s take this a step deeper. In that same survey, 62% found candidates embellishing skills or abilities. But like you, I&amp;rsquo;ve been on the other side of the coin &amp;hellip; writing job descriptions &amp;hellip;that only a true &amp;ldquo;unicorn&amp;rdquo; candidate could meet. Let&amp;rsquo;s call this job description &amp;ldquo;inflation.&amp;rdquo; While I haven&amp;rsquo;t done the research, I would be very surprised if there were no correlation between resume embellishment and job description inflation.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In the end. No one wins. and worse &amp;hellip; we&amp;rsquo;ve created an entire economic system that lacks any credibility or trust.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;the-gig-economy-is-making-things-worse&#34;&gt;The gig economy is making things worse&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As we move into the gig economy, new issues arise making it even harder to verify worker claims. Workers may have many different assignments and may develop a variety of skills and experiences that are hard to document and verify. They may have also taken self-learning or online programs and through those have gained new skills and abilities &amp;hellip; but without the &amp;ldquo;verification&amp;rdquo; of a known entity. As the contingent workforce expands, the task of verifying credentials and experience becomes more difficult.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It all comes back to trust. When we set requirements for a job &amp;hellip; let&amp;rsquo;s say a bachelors degree &amp;hellip; does the job require a bachelor&amp;rsquo;s degree? Is that a requirment to cut down the number of applicants &amp;hellip; does the actual classes and grades matter? How about the institution awarding the degree? What if the degree was attained 15 years ago?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So &amp;hellip; not only do we fundamentally not trust what is on a resume &amp;hellip; do we really even care enough or have time enough to look beyond the surface? And yet &amp;hellip; we spend time and money to run a perfunctory background check &amp;hellip;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;what-if-we-ran-the-numbers&#34;&gt;What if we ran the numbers?&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Let&amp;rsquo;s look at some numbers. The &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.bls.gov/news.release/jolts.nr0.htm&#34;&gt;BLS Job Openings and Labor Turnover Report&lt;/a&gt; recently published (March 16) indicating that January 2018 saw 5.6 million hires in the US.  The average background check runs anywhere from $30 to $300 per candidate. If firms only checked the individuals hired &amp;hellip; that could amount to as much as $1.6 Billion spent by US firms in January.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But Background checks have come a long way from the simplistic verification of ID and criminal history with spot checking of employment and educaiton.  Pre-employment checks have become so common that the federal government began to enforce &amp;ldquo;ban-the-box&amp;rdquo; regulations and laws. 43% of the contingent workforce is now checked at to the same degree as full time employees. Continuous screening is on the rise, and social media screening is growing at a rapid rate. As new screening tools develop, new regulations are sure to follow to more closely regulate for bias.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And because none of this information is shared or vetted between companies &amp;hellip; the duplication of costs is staggering.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;can-blockchain-help&#34;&gt;Can Blockchain help?&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The blockchain is best known as the platform for buying and selling Bitcoins. It was developed for that purpose and has a short history of securing financial transactions. But it is also being used in other areas ranging from the logistics to HR. It is one of the ways being explored to verify credentials such as education, previous employment, skills, and other data frequently required by employers. Blockchain could eliminate resume fraud and increase the integrity of the recruiting process because it is inherently secure.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A blockchain is an encrypted digital ledger of records that are organized into groups of data called blocks and distributed over a network. The blocks are located on servers called nodes linked together, hence the term “chain.” In effect, Blockchain is a way of decentralizing and sharing information across a network.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Whenever a new transaction occurs, the blockchain is authenticated across this network, before the transaction can be included in the next block on the chain. So, the agreement of each node is required to add the block into the chain. Only certain entities such as a specific person or corporation, have a digital ID and can add specific types of information (your college grades and degree, for example). Each node on the network has the same information, and all nodes must agree.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The blockchain creates trust because a copy of the chain showing every transaction is held by the entire network. If someone tries to cheat the system, they can be identified. The data in a block cannot be changed or deleted only added to and if anyone were to attempt to make a false entry, the other nodes would not allow it and the false data would be rejected.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Business-focused private blockchain networks provide for a high degree of security, as well as customized security access rules that can be controlled at the individual or entity level and can be used in many ways from signing legal documents to verifying employment, to establishing employment contracts or validating prior experience.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;numerous-other-benefits-of-blockchain-for-recruitment-and-hr&#34;&gt;Numerous other benefits of blockchain for recruitment and HR&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A foundational talent blockchain could provide numerous additional benefits &amp;hellip; trusted data sets would lead to improved AI matching opportunities. Smart Contracts, which are a fundamental part of the blockchain infrastructure could automate and trigger a number of actions - such as HRIS enrollment, payment start and end dates, establish new contract-based employment, eliminate repetitive processes and increase speed. Automated compliance and transparency is another perk for modern firms and government regulators.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Better yet &amp;hellip; the talent blockchain is already here. Redcell Talent has been working with partners on the design of a state-of-the-art blockchain solution that will launch in the coming months. We&amp;rsquo;ve set up a visual demo that helps to demonstrate some of the uses and invite you to check it out!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you are interested in learning more about the Talent Blockchain and how Redcell Talent can assist you and your organization in getting up to speed with the revolution in talent technology ,be sure to connect with us!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In the mean time &amp;hellip; &lt;a href=&#34;http://blockchain.redcell.ai&#34;&gt;CHECK OUT THE TALENT BLOCKCHAIN DEMO&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;


&lt;p class=&#34;center&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;a href=&#34;http://blockchain.redcell.ai&#34; class=&#34;button __download-link&#34;&gt;Try the Demo!&lt;/a&gt;

  &amp;nbsp;
  &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/getinsomnia/insomnia/releases/vtalent-blockchain&#34;
     class=&#34;button button--no-outline&#34;
     target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;
    View on GitHub
  &lt;/a&gt;
  
&lt;/p&gt;








            </description>
        </item>
        
        <item>
            <title>Is it Really AI? Five Questions to ask before starting your first (next) AI initiative</title>
            <link>https://redcelltalent.com/blog/five-questions-about-artificial-intelligence-hr/</link>
            <pubDate>
                Wed, 21 Feb 2018 00:00:00 +0000
            </pubDate>
            
            <guid>https://redcelltalent.com/blog/five-questions-about-artificial-intelligence-hr/</guid>
            <description>
                


&lt;h2 id=&#34;is-it-really-ai&#34;&gt;Is it really AI?&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;AI is often widely understood as a system that comes to conclusions in a way that resembles a human’s approach. Still, AI is defined differently by different communities and its definition will continue to change with future advances in technology. For instance, some define AI loosely as a computerized system that exhibits behaviour that is commonly thought of as requiring intelligence. Others define AI as a system capable of rationally solving complex problems or taking appropriate actions to achieve its goals in whatever real-world circumstances it encounters. Still others define AI as a great marketing term to connect to an otherwise non-intelligent system as a means of capitalizing on the recent resurgence of the term from its varying iterations through the years.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To help cut through the clutter, we offer a few questions to ask anytime AI is brought into the conversation:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;is-it-based-on-data&#34;&gt;Is it based on data?&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Without data, there is no AI. In fact, rather than starting with assumptions, AI techniques start with data and “learn” certain assumptions based on that data. Many emerging AI technologies and platforms are bringing their own data set … which begs the question, on whose data are the assumptions based?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Additionally, while it’s tempting to think that we could conceive a perfectly rational system, the data used to train AI is often inherently flawed, due to human or other bias, which makes “perfect rationality” nearly impossible to evaluate.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;While smaller organizations are not likely to have enough quality data to develop their own AI, larger organizations would be better off developing and training their own AI or machine learning systems with their own data to better reflect their own unique needs and circumstances. This is especially true regarding utilization within the human or organizational elements of the company. Unlike uniform systems, chemical or biological processes, human behavior varies widely based on environment, conditions, situations, etc. If you are interested in solving human problems unique to your organization, and you have a large enough set of reference data, you are often best served to develop your own models to achieve optimal results.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;is-it-unconcerned-with-the-outcome-of-its-calculations&#34;&gt;Is it unconcerned with the outcome of its calculations?&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Unlike the inherent messiness of human decision-making, an AI’s capacity to make decisions isn’t influenced by ulterior motives or how much sleep it got last night, but is solely focused on the task at hand. Since it doesn’t know good from bad, however, any biases that exist in the data are perpetuated. This is where the need for solid design is paramount. You may not be first at launching your AI-based services, but if your design and your data are superior, you will have the superior product in the end.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It is important, however, not to ascribe human likeness to what is essentially just complex math. Like any technology system, bad data in equals bad data out &amp;hellip; the difference is that an AI system is often tied to automation more so than human controlled systems. And an AI system cannot be reverse-engineered to discover where the calculations went wrong &amp;hellip; which means poor data and poor planning can yield potentially massive re-work and costs. But never fear, the AI won&amp;rsquo;t worry about it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;are-its-abilities-learned-rather-than-programmed&#34;&gt;Are its abilities learned rather than programmed?&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;AI can improve iteratively on its own — without being programmed every step of the way, it can learn from its experiences and improve at making future predictions and decisions, resulting in increasingly sophisticated abilities.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Recent advances in machine learning have largely been due to the growth of deep learning — a subfield of machine learning. Deep learning borrows from the structure of the brain, by linking lots of simple “neuron” like structures together to do interesting things in a neural network. By stacking many layers of these artificial neurons together (hence “deep”), the network as a whole can learn to do complex tasks. Interestingly, “neurons” in these layers often end up performing specific roles, such as recognizing edges, or the outline of a specific object. The unique strength of deep learning is that these sub-tasks — often known as “features” — are learned directly from the data, rather than being specified by programmers.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Managers that want blunt control over their models are best to avoid AI and ML altogether as the internal calculations (generally derived through back propagation) are generally unknowable. A deep-learning system doesn’t have any explanatory power. A black box cannot investigate cause. Indeed, the more powerful the deep-learning system becomes, the more opaque it can become.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;is-it-constantly-evolving&#34;&gt;Is it constantly evolving?&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;AI models continually gain in value over time. For this reason, even initiating a clean data collection initiative sooner than later is preferable to waiting or utilizing an external data set.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Let’s take a real-life example for HR: recognizing ideal fit in applicant selection. A classic AI approach would rely upon a human expert trying to distill their own decision-making process and then codify it in the algorithm. For instance, in our applicant tracking system, we might flag specific words that are relevant to the job, or connected to a specific certification. With deep learning, however, we can directly feed profiles of existing employees labeled to indicate whether they’re high-performing or not, and our neural network will learn to pick out the most useful features of the profile for this particular task. This is a classic example of “supervised learning”: we provide some inputs and some desired outputs, and the algorithm learns to map from one to the other.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;From this perspective, the more data, the more learning the model can handle, though it is also important to understand that current iterations should be narrow in scope: ie. one job type at a time.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We can also do away with the labels entirely, and ask the algorithm to group the traits or “competencies” that have something in common.This process is known as clustering, and it’s a type of unsupervised learning. Here we’re not providing supervision in the form of labels, we’re simply using deep learning to find structure in the data. In our example, perhaps our profile includes many different competency types — academic, hands-on experiences, and software — and it’d be useful to cluster these before trying to figure out which competencies in each cluster are most important for selection.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In either case, business needs change dynamically, but not swiftly, and as data is continually fed into the model, the model gains capabilities, potentially being able to predict future occupational skill groupings, or ideal skill groupings.&lt;/p&gt;


&lt;p class=&#34;center&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;a href=&#34;http://blockchain.redcell.ai&#34; class=&#34;button __download-link&#34;&gt;Try the Demo!&lt;/a&gt;

  &amp;nbsp;
  &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/getinsomnia/insomnia/releases/vfive-questions-about-artificial-intelligence-hr&#34;
     class=&#34;button button--no-outline&#34;
     target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;
    View on GitHub
  &lt;/a&gt;
  
&lt;/p&gt;








            </description>
        </item>
        
        <item>
            <title>AI and Talent Management.</title>
            <link>https://redcelltalent.com/blog/talent-ai-organizational-development/</link>
            <pubDate>
                Wed, 14 Feb 2018 22:01:22 -0700
            </pubDate>
            
            <guid>https://redcelltalent.com/blog/talent-ai-organizational-development/</guid>
            <description>
                


&lt;p&gt;For decades, artificial intelligence (AI) researchers have sought to enable computers to perform a wide range of tasks once thought to be reserved for humans. In recent years, the technology has moved from science fiction into real life: AI programs can play games, recognize faces and speech, learn, and make informed decisions.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As striking as AI programs may be (and as potentially unsettling the prospect may be to tech leaders and average citizens alike), the cognitive technologies behind artificial intelligence are already having a real impact on many people’s lives and work. AI-based technologies include machine learning, computer vision, speech recognition, natural language processing, and robotics;1 they are powerful, scalable, and improving at an exponential rate. Developers are working on implementing AI solutions in everything from self-driving cars to swarms of autonomous drones, from “intelligent” robots to stunningly accurate speech translation.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And while HR may not have lead the way, human resources professionals are seeking—and finding—applications to improve services; indeed, cognitive technologies could eventually revolutionize every facet of HR operations. The rise of more sophisticated cognitive technologies is, of course, critical to that transformation, aiding advances in numerous areas:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Rules-based systems capture and use experts’ knowledge to provide answers to tricky but routine problems. As this decades-old form of AI grows more sophisticated, users may forget they aren’t conversing with a real person, in fact, most of us are tuned via texting to accept increased interaction with AI agents.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Speech recognition transcribes human speech automatically and accurately. The technology is improving as machines collect more examples of conversation. This has obvious value for dictation, phone assistance, and much more.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Machine translation, as the name indicates, translates text or speech from one language to another. Significant advances have been made in this field in only the past year. Machine translation has obvious implications for global companies via international relations, or for defense, and intelligence as well as, in our multilingual society, numerous domestic applications.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Computer vision is the ability to identify objects, scenes, and activities in naturally occurring images. It’s how Facebook sorts millions of users’ photos, but it can also scan medical images for indications of disease and identify criminals from surveillance footage. Soon it will allow HR to quickly scan workers to establish access permissions and identify positive and negative work patterns.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Machine learning takes place without explicit programming. By trial and error, computers learn how to learn, mining information to discover patterns in data that can help predict future events. The larger the datasets, the easier it is to accurately gauge normal or abnormal behavior. When your email program flags a message as spam, or your credit card company warns you of a potentially fraudulent use of your card, machine learning may be involved. Deep learning is a branch of machine learning involving artificial neural networks inspired by the brain’s structure and function.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Natural language processing refers to the complex and difficult task of organizing and understanding language in a human way. This goes far beyond interpreting search queries, or translating between Mandarin and English text. Combined with machine learning, a system can scan websites for discussions of specific topics even if the user didn’t input precise search terms. Computers can identify all the people and places mentioned in a document or extract terms and conditions from contracts. As with all AI-enabled technology, these become smarter as they consume more accurate data—and as developers integrate complementary technologies such as machine translation and natural language processing.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;weighing-human-involvement-required&#34;&gt;Weighing Human Involvement Required&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;canvas id=&#34;myChart&#34; width=&#34;300&#34; height=&#34;200&#34;&gt;&lt;/canvas&gt;

&lt;script&gt;
var ctx = document.getElementById(&#34;myChart&#34;).getContext(&#39;2d&#39;);
var myChart = new Chart(ctx, {
    type: &#39;bar&#39;,
    data: {
        labels: [&#34;Collect Data&#34;, &#34;Geo-tagging&#34;, &#34;Analyze Tweets&#34;, &#34;Ranking Candidates&#34;],
        datasets: [{
            label: &#39;% Human Involvement Required&#39;,
            data: [5, 5, 15, 30],
            backgroundColor: [
                &#39;rgba(255, 99, 132, 0.2)&#39;,
                &#39;rgba(54, 162, 235, 0.2)&#39;,
                &#39;rgba(255, 206, 86, 0.2)&#39;,
                &#39;rgba(75, 192, 192, 0.2)&#39;

            ],
            borderColor: [
                &#39;rgba(255,99,132,1)&#39;,
                &#39;rgba(54, 162, 235, 1)&#39;,
                &#39;rgba(255, 206, 86, 1)&#39;,
                &#39;rgba(75, 192, 192, 1)&#39;

            ],
            borderWidth: 1
        }]
    },
    options: {
        scales: {
            yAxes: [{
                ticks: {
                    beginAtZero:true
                }
            }]
        }
    }
});
&lt;/script&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;how-ai-can-benefit-hr-in-workforce-development&#34;&gt;How AI can benefit HR in workforce development&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you spend much time in or around HR departments, you’re likely to hear some common complaints:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“We don’t have enough people to keep up.”
“We have to go through thousands of resumes on this one.”
“The paperwork is killing our productivity.”
“We don’t know because we can’t track events and incidents like that.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;These are exactly the sort of problems cognitive technologies can address, and the solutions often resolve around how work is done. Here is where the need for HR adoption of AI technologies is most prevalent. Sometimes it is helpful to view the issue from the perspective of a front line worker. While these are not necessarily discrete categories, HR&amp;rsquo;s utilization of AI in workforce design and development can be divided into four approaches to automation:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;canvas id=&#34;radar-chart&#34; width=&#34;300&#34; height=&#34;300&#34;&gt;&lt;/canvas&gt;

&lt;script&gt;
new Chart(document.getElementById(&#34;radar-chart&#34;), {
    type: &#39;radar&#39;,
    data: {
      labels: [&#34;Relieve&#34;, &#34;Split up&#34;, &#34;Replace&#34;, &#34;Augment&#34;],
      datasets: [
        {
          label: &#34;2000&#34;,
          fill: true,
          backgroundColor: &#34;rgba(179,181,198,0.2)&#34;,
          borderColor: &#34;rgba(179,181,198,1)&#34;,
          pointBorderColor: &#34;#fff&#34;,
          pointBackgroundColor: &#34;rgba(179,181,198,1)&#34;,
          data: [8.75,35.85,55.56,3.54]
        }, {
          label: &#34;2025&#34;,
          fill: true,
          backgroundColor: &#34;rgba(255,99,132,0.2)&#34;,
          borderColor: &#34;rgba(255,99,132,1)&#34;,
          pointBorderColor: &#34;#fff&#34;,
          pointBackgroundColor: &#34;rgba(255,99,132,1)&#34;,
          pointBorderColor: &#34;#fff&#34;,
          data: [25.45, 15.55, 15.75, 65.55]
        }
      ]
    },
    options: {
      title: {
        display: true,
        text: &#39;Perceptions of AI Potential for Workforce Development&#39;
      }
    }
});
&lt;/script&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Relieve&lt;/em&gt;. Technology takes over mundane tasks, freeing workers for more valuable work. The Associated Press, for example, uses machines to write routine corporate earnings stories so that journalists can focus on in-depth reporting.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The relieve approach allows departments to focus on reducing backlogs or shifting workers to higher-value tasks. For instance, an automated engineering planning system saved expert engineers of the Hong Kong subway system two days of work per week, allowing them to devote their time to harder problems requiring human interaction and negotiation.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Split up&lt;/em&gt;. This approach involves breaking a job into steps or pieces and automating as many as possible, leaving humans to do the remainder and perhaps supervise the automated work. Relying on machine language translation and leaving professional translators to “clean up” the results is one example. Several entities, from the White House to US Citizenship and Immigration Services, have chatbots designed to answer basic questions and leave complicated responses to a human. The difference between relieve and split up is that with the latter, not all tasks given to computers are routine, mundane tasks.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Replace&lt;/em&gt;. In this approach, technology is used to do an entire job once performed by a human. The post office uses handwriting recognition to sort mail by ZIP code; some machines can process 18,000 pieces of mail an hour. The best opportunities for replace include repetitive tasks with uniform components, decision making that follows simple rules, and tasks with a finite number of possible outcomes. If you’ve ever fought a computer program because your situation lay outside the narrow possibilities its designers imagined, you know how frustrating it can be. Luckily, replacement need not be total.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Augment&lt;/em&gt; and extend. In this approach, technology makes workers more effective by complementing their skills. This is the true promise of AI: humans and computers combining their strengths to achieve faster and better results, often doing what humans simply couldn’t do before.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When technology is designed to augment, humans are still very much in the driver’s seat. An example is IBM’s Watson for Oncology, which recommends individual cancer treatments to physicians, citing evidence and a confidence score for each recommendation, to help them make more fully informed decisions.
As AI tools continue to develop alongside additive technologies like augmented reality and voice-operated systems, the potential for human augmentation becomes a greater and more powerful option.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;hr-should-lead-the-way-to-an-augmented-future&#34;&gt;HR Should lead the way to an augmented future&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Rather than leading to the promised disruption of recruiting  practices, the applicant tracking system (ATS) and its ecosystem of talent management add-ons has generated a dysphoria for hiring managers. The deluge of paper resumes has simply been replaced by a tsunami of digital paperwork with limited to no improvement in outcomes. As damaging as this has been to cost and efficiency, it is the role the ATS has played in de-emphasizing human interaction that has caused the greatest distress.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;While the recruiter’s role is synonymous with sourcing, the purpose of the hiring process is ultimately retention and productivity. According to a recent study published in the Harvard Business Review, nearly 80% of employee turnover is due to bad hiring decisions which is estimated to cost  the company as much as two and half times the person’s annualized salary.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To address these issues, Redcell has pioneered the concept of augmented sourcing. Augmented sourcing places human interaction at the center, and technology in the supporting role, which creates efficiencies for both. We believe that by augmenting sourcing strategies, (and all of the HR suite of responsibilities) with advanced technology, we can assist companies in significantly improving critical hiring and retention outcomes while reducing average cost per hire &amp;hellip; at the speed of business.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you would like to learn more. Contact us about our free Process Audit.&lt;/p&gt;


&lt;p class=&#34;center&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;a href=&#34;http://blockchain.redcell.ai&#34; class=&#34;button __download-link&#34;&gt;Try the Demo!&lt;/a&gt;

  &amp;nbsp;
  &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/getinsomnia/insomnia/releases/vtalent-ai-organizational-development&#34;
     class=&#34;button button--no-outline&#34;
     target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;
    View on GitHub
  &lt;/a&gt;
  
&lt;/p&gt;








            </description>
        </item>
        
        <item>
            <title>A Guide to AI in HR</title>
            <link>https://redcelltalent.com/blog/guide-artificial-intelligence-human-resources/</link>
            <pubDate>
                Fri, 19 Jan 2018 22:01:22 -0700
            </pubDate>
            
            <guid>https://redcelltalent.com/blog/guide-artificial-intelligence-human-resources/</guid>
            <description>
                


&lt;h1 id=&#34;a-guide-to-understanding-artificial-intelligence-in-human-resources&#34;&gt;A guide to understanding Artificial Intelligence in human resources.&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;With a veritable explosion of investment, 2018 is clearly the year of artificial intelligence hype, and while human resources (HR) remains at the fringe of discussion, it is poised for disruption.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But what does artificial intelligence really mean?  How close are we to achieving “meaningful use” - to steal a term from healthcare? Should you as a recruiter or HR Director care? Is your job or role at risk?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Without doubt, the questions outweigh the answers. While we won’t address all of those questions here, we do want to introduce several key concepts that underlie AI - and for professionals familiar with statistical analysis and probability, this will likely be an approach that makes more sense than the puffery that abounds.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://res.cloudinary.com/victorydev/image/upload/v1518442988/HR-Recruitment_tq1nzf.jpg?raw=true&#34; alt=&#34;Image of AI in HR&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;At the heart of an AI application lies the Neural Network, or in its simplest form the Artificial Neural Network (ANN). You will also encounter the Convolutional Neural Network (CNN) and finally Recurrent Neural Networks (RNN).
These neural networks attempt to model the human brain - or how the brain processes information, and each has its specific use case.  Understanding the differences between ANN-CNN-RNN will help you identify both the scale and scope of a given task you are attempting, and help you avoid unnecessary costs when working with organizations offering AI solutions.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In brief, each type of neural net is aligned with a complex use case like classification, clustering and prediction. For example, image recognition and face recognition use CNN while Natural Language Processing (NLP) relies on RNN. ANN, the simpler ones of all the neural networks is often used for predictions involving numerical data.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;An organization attempting to develop a chatbot interface might utilize RNN. An organization looking to add facial recognition to the patient intake process would rely on CNN, and a practice interested in predicting the probability of patient compliance would develop ANN models.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Most often, Artificial Intelligence is assumed to have predictive abilities combined with sight and speech processing .. in this use case all three deep learning models must be combined in a highly complex system … which very few AI applications do successfully at this point.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;going-a-little-deeper-down-the-rabbit-hole&#34;&gt;Going a little deeper down the rabbit hole.&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For most immediate applications, the ANN is most appropriate … as prediction is generally the most valuable aid in a business setting. Prediction, however, doesn’t require artificial intelligence. In fact, the output of an ANN may be frustrating for HR as the weights within the hidden layers are just that … hidden.  With a general computer algorithm, a data scientist will set weights … generally based on previous studies or observations … and those weights will be visible and apparent.  The ANN generally works across so a large network of vectors that visualizing every weight is not only impractical … it is impossible.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;AI is a “black box” that is often impenetrable … even though it is mathematical.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A CNN on the other hand will learn to recognize patterns across space. This is particularly useful in visually-oriented applications such as recognizing a photo ID, or being able to connect a video stream of a person’s face to a stored photo ID. A CNN will learn to recognize components of an image (e.g., lines, curves, etc.) and then learn to combine these components to recognize larger structures (e.g., faces, objects, etc.).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Finally, the RNN will similarly learn to recognize patterns, but will do so across time. So a RNN that is trained to translate text might learn that &amp;ldquo;dog&amp;rdquo; should be translated differently if preceded by the word &amp;ldquo;hot&amp;rdquo;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The mechanism by which the three kinds of NNs represent these patterns is different. In the case of a CNN, you are looking for the same patterns on all the different subfields of the image. In the case of a RNN you are (in the simplest case) feeding the hidden layers from the previous step as an additional input into the next step. While the RNN builds up memory in this process, it is not looking for the same patterns over different slices of time in the same way that a CNN is looking for the same patterns over different regions of space.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You could run a RNN on a single image for image captioning, for instance, and the meaning of &amp;ldquo;time&amp;rdquo; would simply be the order in which different parts of the image are processed. So objects initially processed will inform the captioning of later objects processed.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Here&amp;rsquo;s a sample diagram of what&amp;rsquo;s going on inside a type of RNN:
&lt;img src=&#34;https://res.cloudinary.com/victorydev/image/upload/v1518443787/LSTM-RNN_e2bipi.jpg?raw=true&#34; alt=&#34;Image of an LSTM&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;so-how-should-hr-approach-ai-to-solve-a-particular-problem&#34;&gt;So how should HR approach AI to solve a particular problem?&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It should first be noted that the expansion, affordability and availability of AI tools is such now that even individual departments can easily afford to develop specific implementations.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As a data scientist, before approaching an algorithm the first thing we should always ask is what kind of dataset we have. If the problem is Classification ( e.g. predicting the likelihood of the group of skills in a resume being a fit for a job opening) the kind of algorithms you would use, would be defined by the kind of dataset you have and the state of that data.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The next thing you should look at is the business objective of the problem. An objective to understand the “reasons” for a particular problem - like the risk factors causing someone to leave the company - makes it an Inference Problem.
In the Inference problem the objective is more to understand the relationship between features and the response/dependent variables. In that case one would prefer linear or less complex models since they are interpretable.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A business objective to focus more on accuracy and a correct prediction score rather than understanding the data, is a Prediction Problem. You then have the luxury to choose algorithms that focus on prediction accuracy. Usually, complex or “black box” models like the ANN will work well for a Prediction Problem. But is is crucial to understand that Interpretability is very low for such models as the focus is on getting an accurate prediction rather than an inference or understanding of the relationships within the data.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;limitations-of-any-given-model&#34;&gt;Limitations of any given model&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There is no universal algorithm that works best on all kinds of dataset problems. Because of this, any implementation may need to try multiple algorithms to find which one works well on the specific dataset in question. Because of this, may organizations will simply adopt the largest AI solution that can be easily afforded. The danger in this approach is trusting that the model itself was correctly designed.  Without sufficient design, no AI will be useful.
Normally it&amp;rsquo;s a good approach to start with simple algorithms ( like logistic regression or other simple linear counterparts) and build on the complexity as you progress.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In the end, if you are seeking highly accurate prediction without needing to have an explanation, the ANN is ideal. CNN &amp;amp; RNN are deep learning approaches which are best used on text, speech and image data. All Neural Networks are “non-interpretable” models requiring immense computing resources and work best with lots of data to train the weights in the model. Using AI is ideal for a computer vision or NLP task requiring great accuracy, but it is not best for an everyday data science task.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;takeaways-for-hr&#34;&gt;Takeaways for HR&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So what does this mean for HR? There are a number of use cases for the implementation of AI in HR. With existing restraints to selection tools, some immediate applications include:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Turnover Prediction&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Fit Prediction&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Performance Analysis&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Pay Negotiation or Modeling&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Recruiting Messaging Personalization&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Programmatic Recruiting&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;


&lt;p class=&#34;center&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;a href=&#34;http://blockchain.redcell.ai&#34; class=&#34;button __download-link&#34;&gt;Try the Demo!&lt;/a&gt;

  &amp;nbsp;
  &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/getinsomnia/insomnia/releases/vguide-artificial-intelligence-human-resources&#34;
     class=&#34;button button--no-outline&#34;
     target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;
    View on GitHub
  &lt;/a&gt;
  
&lt;/p&gt;








            </description>
        </item>
        
        <item>
            <title>You&#39;re Invited to The Slack Team</title>
            <link>https://redcelltalent.com/blog/slack-channel/</link>
            <pubDate>
                Thu, 11 Jan 2018 00:00:00 +0000
            </pubDate>
            
            <guid>https://redcelltalent.com/blog/slack-channel/</guid>
            <description>
                
&lt;p&gt;Since the Launch of customized services and our open knowledge exchange in late 2017, many individuals and organizations have submitted bugs, asked questions, and proposed features via email.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;While we love email, this is not always the most suitable medium for discussion. Now, Thanks to a suggestion from our growing community, we have created a public Slack Team that anyone can join.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p style=&#34;text-align:center;&#34;&gt;
&lt;a class=&#34;button&#34; href=&#34;https://join.slack.com/t/redcell-ai/shared_invite/enQtMzE0MDUwMjI5NDk1LWQ4ZTYzN2IxY2Q4NzQ4MzQ1Y2Q0MTQ0NmJhZjJmZjMzMjdkMWNmMWU5ODE2ZTA2Mzc5ZGQ0Mjk0MTM5ZWU5Y2U&#34;&gt;Join Redcell on Slack&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So, head on over, introduce yourself, and join in on the discussion.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;See you there!&lt;/p&gt;


&lt;p class=&#34;center&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;a href=&#34;http://blockchain.redcell.ai&#34; class=&#34;button __download-link&#34;&gt;Try the Demo!&lt;/a&gt;

  &amp;nbsp;
  &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/getinsomnia/insomnia/releases/vslack-channel&#34;
     class=&#34;button button--no-outline&#34;
     target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;
    View on GitHub
  &lt;/a&gt;
  
&lt;/p&gt;








            </description>
        </item>
        
        <item>
            <title>Alas, you are offline!</title>
            <link>https://redcelltalent.com/404/</link>
            <pubDate>
                Thu, 04 Jan 2018 00:00:00 +0000
            </pubDate>
            
            <guid>https://redcelltalent.com/404/</guid>
            <description>
                
&lt;p&gt;Hey! You&amp;rsquo;re offline. Go grab a connection. We&amp;rsquo;ll wait right here for you.&lt;/p&gt;


&lt;p class=&#34;center&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;a href=&#34;http://blockchain.redcell.ai&#34; class=&#34;button __download-link&#34;&gt;Try the Demo!&lt;/a&gt;

  &amp;nbsp;
  &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/getinsomnia/insomnia/releases/v&#34;
     class=&#34;button button--no-outline&#34;
     target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;
    View on GitHub
  &lt;/a&gt;
  
&lt;/p&gt;








            </description>
        </item>
        
        <item>
            <title>Alas, you are offline!</title>
            <link>https://redcelltalent.com/offline/</link>
            <pubDate>
                Thu, 04 Jan 2018 00:00:00 +0000
            </pubDate>
            
            <guid>https://redcelltalent.com/offline/</guid>
            <description>
                
&lt;p&gt;Hey! You&amp;rsquo;re offline. Go grab a connection. We&amp;rsquo;ll wait right here for you.&lt;/p&gt;


&lt;p class=&#34;center&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;a href=&#34;http://blockchain.redcell.ai&#34; class=&#34;button __download-link&#34;&gt;Try the Demo!&lt;/a&gt;

  &amp;nbsp;
  &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/getinsomnia/insomnia/releases/v&#34;
     class=&#34;button button--no-outline&#34;
     target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;
    View on GitHub
  &lt;/a&gt;
  
&lt;/p&gt;








            </description>
        </item>
        
        <item>
            <title>Understanding the Hire, and how it needs to change</title>
            <link>https://redcelltalent.com/blog/hire-process/</link>
            <pubDate>
                Tue, 28 Nov 2017 00:00:00 +0000
            </pubDate>
            
            <guid>https://redcelltalent.com/blog/hire-process/</guid>
            <description>
                


&lt;h1 id=&#34;the-1970-s-called-and-they-want-the-color-of-their-parachute-back&#34;&gt;The 1970’s called and they want the color of their parachute back…&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;From the top I will note that this is not intended to be a thought-piece about Dick Bolles or her eponymous career discovery book, “What color is your parachute?” [first published in 1975] - it is, however, intended to be a bit of a diatribe against “the resume” and the lack of innovation in general in the field of career advisement.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;How is it, that we have nearly arrived at two decades past the year 2000 and are closer to landing a person on Mars than we are to smoothly ensuring the civilian career success of a soldier? - or a graduating student? - or a parent returning to work? - or a technician needing to transition out of an industry that is shutting down?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;How is it that we are still using a Resume as the primary currency of the business transaction that is “the hire?” Surely … somewhere there is a solution to the insanity that is a job search - but everywhere we look, the trends point further away from career and more toward a gig economy of transient tasks stitched together via dated algorithms of what it means to be human in an occupation.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;What is more amazing to me is the near lack of any meaningful change in the last 50 years - not just in how individuals and companies interact, but in the resources supplied to provide those individuals with insight into how to select a career path they will most enjoy and in which they can succeed. Is our path to success rooted in a psychological profile? Is it best determined by a standardized test? Our we better off with a technical skill assessment? Or are we merely destined to wander along until we manage to strike the right chord or die trying….&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Personally, I’ve been working the issue through my mind for the better part of a decade [which suggests that I may not be the right one to come up with the right answer] - and every once in awhile I find it useful to walk through the process in the hope that some new nugget will reveal itself.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As it happens, this weekend was one of those moments and so I thought I would share my thoughts with a broader audience as either a means of soliciting greater insight than I can muster on my own … or perhaps as some small cry for help…&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you are willing to follow-along on this thought excursion, join me first in the perspective of the hiring manager. In my observation, the greatest challenge in selection and management of human capital lies at the transactional level.  Decision-making surrounding a hire, termination, promotion, tasking, reporting, team construction, project assignment, etc. rests on a manager’s or organization’s ability to observe, infer, trust and ultimately make the correct choice.  A myriad of options, products and tools exist to assist in a decision process that often comes down to intuition in the face of what is essentially unknowable complexity.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&#34;the-hire&#34;&gt;The Hire&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Using the “hire” as an example, we will consider the various decision points the typical organization navigates to arrive at a staffing decision.  The process generally begins with the recognition of a need for additional staff to perform a variety of functions, some of which are obvious tasks, some of which are not.  Let’s say an organization decides to hire additional sales staff.  Assuming that the organization has hired sales professionals in the past, they may have a “template” to work from, perhaps in the form of a job description.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The job description typically references a set of requirements and broad achievements that a candidate must have in order to be considered for selection.  When boiled down, the list typically includes: x years of experience with x skills, x level of education, and x certifications.  Beyond that are varying amounts of narrative designed to narrow the field, but which is typically either a template from a professional association or written by someone in the human resources office that is assisting in the management of the process.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;job-classification&#34;&gt;Job Classification&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To this point, the job description may be symbolized in a succinct code such as the taxonomy created by the US Department of Labor’s O*Net occupational database and taxonomy.  The DOL O*Net SOC taxonomy classifies occupations by major groups, minor groups, broad occupations, detailed occupations.  Unclassified lists of “competencies” in a text format are further assigned to each SOC classification to create a codified narrative useful for creating job descriptions and establishing job requirements.  Each SOC is defined by Tasks, Tools &amp;amp; Technology, Knowledge, Skills, Abilities, Work Activities and Work Context.  As an example, the code for a Sales Manager is 11-2022.00 and a detailed description of this jobs requirements can be found by clicking here.  Anecdotally, few employers use this system to classify and list jobs as it is admittedly slow to keep up with job requirements and titles.  A significant limitation of this system and taxonomy is a lack of classification structure for assigned knowledge skills and abilities that would permit a more detailed gap analysis for workers and jobs.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Regardless of how an employer derives their job requirements, the initial job description is generally placed in an online system to which a number of additional screening “questions” may be added to narrow the pool of applicants.  Applicants submit a narrative document known as the “resume,” as evidence of their qualifications.  Resumes, being narrative in nature, have few standards, but can be “parsed” into discrete data fields (generally aligned to those basic requirements listed above).  Additional measures may be added to further filter the pool including electronic and paper forms that require the applicant to rewrite the content of the resume in a format determined by the employer to more easily baseline and compare information presented by the applicant.  At this point, the process typically takes a dramatic turn into the realm of the subjective (eg. the “Interview”).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A few pieces of relevant information are rarely sufficient to confirm that an individual both has the capabilities to do the work required, and has mastered certain competencies to a sufficient degree to successfully perform the functions of the job on a regular and satisfactory basis.  Thus, any number of additional and invariably more subjective actions come into play ranging from pre-tests, to simulations, to credit checks, drug tests, psychological profiles, peer interviews, background investigations, and the hiring manager interview.  If we are honest, the final selection boils down to the gut feel of the selecting official, whose motivations are inscrutable, but ideally backed by enough objective evidence to avoid running afoul of federal and state regulations.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;From the perspective of the job seeker, the entire process is not only intimidating and confusing, but devaluing of their own perspective of their capabilities, motivations and capacity to perform the requirements of the job.  Worse, a candidate generally has no idea whether they qualify or not for a position.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Undoubtedly, all parties involved would be better served by a cleaner, clearer system that allows candidates to know if they qualify for a position, and managers to have confidence that their final slate of candidates has the capability to perform the required functions.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To extend the analogy a step further, the same level of obfuscation exists within the vast majority of decisions surrounding human capital at the transactional level: how does an employer effectively transition and grow effective workers into new roles (promotion), how does an employer efficiently train, retrain and assess changing skill requirements (development), how does an employer assess and compare effectiveness of employees (termination, motivation and retention).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To begin to address the inefficiencies and high costs associated with worker selection, promotion and development, we have actually developed a more cohesive taxonomy or means of classifying work requirements at the fundamental unit of work, the competency.  To do so, we begin with the definition of competency and create a means by which these competencies can be rapidly assigned, measured, articulated and codified, not only as work requirements, but as metrics and learning objects.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;classification-of-competencies&#34;&gt;Classification of Competencies&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To properly classify a set of competencies and thereby create a cohesive taxonomy, it is first necessary to define how the term is being considered and used.  The US Department of Labor developed a Competency system that organizes competencies into nine tiers that fall into three broad categories: Occupation Related, Industry Related, and Foundational Competencies.  Given the industry adoption and level of work that has gone into defining work according to this framework, it does supply a solid framework.  It does not, however, provide a suitable or standard classification system to organize those competencies.  Neither does it address the weighting of competencies, how they are measured and levels of mastery.  Rather, competency is the general term used for a range of skills, abilities, knowledge, and familiarization of the same.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Such a broad definition deflates the literal sense of the word “competence” which refers to the possession of a required skill knowledge, qualification, or capacity.  In addition to “possession” there is a sense of sufficiency associated with the word that relies upon an assumption that a person who has competence in skill not only possesses the skill, but possesses it in sufficient quality and efficacy as to be able to function in a variety of circumstances.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It is this sense of competency that interests an employer.  They are not merely interested in whether an individual knows how to do a task, or knows certain information … but how well they can perform the task or recall that information under pressure and a variety of circumstances.  A taxonomy that organizes skills, abilities and knowledge, but provides no differentiation in mastery cannot adequately be considered a competency taxonomy.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This being said, I recognize the fact that any classification process or system can easily become mired in unnecessary detail, and therefore, it is the purpose of this organization to create a means by which partners can rapidly align occupational needs to the individuals that can best demonstrate the necessary level of competency required. Desiring to create efficiencies rather than further complication, the taxonomy we have begun to embed in our online tools (check out the STEMType and CCFIT tools), while aware of the broader research on the subject of classification of workplace competencies dating back to the early 70’s - we chose to adopt portions of prevalent approaches into a system more amenable to practical application in the workplace.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To do so, I present the concept of the “job model” as a measure of sets of competencies at defined levels of mastery with a definition of competency reflective of the 1797 latin derivation of competere (also derivative of compete) meaning, “sufficiency of qualification.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;the-job-model&#34;&gt;The Job Model&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As previously discussed, the job description is generally little more than a poor parody of actual job requirements.  Not unlike what is found in our education system, a job description describes job qualifications in terms of time rather than mastery.  Assumed in this model is the notion that an individual bearing a similar job title from a similar sized employer is the individual optimally suited for a given position.  The “qualification by time in grade” concept creates significant barriers for talent development and is more apt to result in underperformance as well as underemployment. [incidentally this is a key point of failure for military in transition] In turn, job candidates are left without a clear means by which they can become qualified.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In the job model framework, time becomes only one means by which mastery can be demonstrated, but co-equal with more definitive and relevant measures such as proof by examination, demonstration, and certification.  Employers may still select time utilizing a given skill as a measure of maturity or sufficiency, but would be wise to consider more relevant testing mechanisms as supplemental proof of sufficiency of qualification (and skill relevance).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;classification&#34;&gt;Classification&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;One of the greatest challenges in designing a taxonomy is in the creation of a suitable taxonomy that is flexible, scalable, and ultimately something that can be implemented within various data systems and constraints.  Additionally, we face the question of adoption versus protection.  In a world of open source versus proprietary, both options have their advantages.  Leaving a taxonomy open and free increases the likelihood of adoption, but exposes the creator to obscurity and irrelevance.  Holding tight proprietary restrictions on a model can lead to income through various methods such as licensing and product development, but adoption may be slow and ultimately lead to the death of the model outside of its few implementations.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Given the complexities involved in the creation of a classification system, and the myriad options available, it makes some sense, even for a proprietary solution, to create linkages from the model to known systems already in wide adoption ie, the U.S. Department of Labor’s O*Net job taxonomy.  At first glance, the O*Net taxonomy appears to be, and is for the most part, a comprehensive solution into which millions of dollars and work-hours have been invested.  Undoubtedly, it is the logical basis from which a viable taxonomy may arise.  The following section outlines the key components of this taxonomy, deficits, and adjustments that need to be made to form the basis of a job model that provides value to the career advisement process.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;O*NET®-SOC (the following section contains whole and partial “quoted material” from documents prepared by the National Center for O*Net Development, December 2010)&lt;br /&gt;
“The O*NET®-SOC (Occupational Information Network-Standard Occupational Classification) occupational taxonomy is currently operating on revisions instituted in 2010.  [ Given the average length of time between revisions, it is expected that a new revision will be released between 2012 and 2016. The database, however is updated on an annual basis.] The O*NET-SOC 2010 taxonomy includes 1110 occupational titles, 974 of which represent O*NET data-level occupations. Data-level occupations are those for which the O*NET program collects data from job incumbents, occupation experts, and occupational analysts. Data are collected on a wide variety of variables and scales, such as occupational characteristics and worker requirements drawn from the O*NET Content Model &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.onetcenter.org/content.html&#34;&gt;O*Net Link&lt;/a&gt;.
The O*NET-SOC 2009 taxonomy contained 1102 occupational titles, 965 of which represented O*NET data-level occupations.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The structure of the SOC system includes four levels of aggregation: 23 major groups, 96 minor groups, 449 broad occupations and 821 detailed occupations. All SOC occupations are assigned a six-digit code. The first and second digits represent the major group; the third digit represents the minor group; the fourth and fifth digits represent the broad occupation; and the sixth digit represents the detailed occupation. The 23 major groups of the SOC include:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;table&gt;
&lt;thead&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;th align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;O*Net Code&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;Occupation Group&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/thead&gt;

&lt;tbody&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;11-0000&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;Management Occupations&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;

&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;13-0000&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;Business and Financial Operations Occupations&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;

&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;15-0000&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;Computer and Mathematical Occupations&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;

&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;17-0000&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;Architecture and Engineering Occupations&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;

&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;19-0000&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;Life, Physical, and Social Science Occupations&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;

&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;21-0000&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;Community and Social Services Occupations&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;

&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;23-0000&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;Legal Occupations&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;

&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;25-0000&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;Education, Training, and Library Occupations&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;

&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;27-0000&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;Arts, Design, Entertainment, Sports, and Media Occupations&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;

&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;29-0000&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;Healthcare Practitioners and Technical Occupations&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;

&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;31-0000&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;Healthcare Support Occupations&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;

&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;33-0000&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;Protective Service Occupations&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;

&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;35-0000&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;Food Preparation and Serving Related Occupations&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;

&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;37-0000&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;Building and Grounds Cleaning and Maintenance Occupations&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;

&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;39-0000&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;Personal Care and Service Occupations&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;

&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;41-0000&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;Sales and Related Occupations&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;

&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;43-0000&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;Office and Administrative Support Occupations&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;

&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;45-0000&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;Farming, Fishing, and Forestry Occupations&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;

&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;47-0000&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;Construction and Extraction Occupations&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;

&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;49-0000&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;Installation, Maintenance, and Repair Occupations&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;

&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;51-0000&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;Production Occupations&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;

&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;53-0000&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;Transportation and Material Moving Occupations&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;

&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;55-0000&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;Military Specific Occupations&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/tbody&gt;
&lt;/table&gt;

&lt;p&gt;SOC minor groups, broad occupations, and detailed occupations are assigned codes related to the corresponding major groups. For example:&lt;br /&gt;
| O*Net Code | Occupation Group |
| :&amp;mdash;         |     :&amp;mdash;      |&lt;br /&gt;
|19-0000 |Life, Physical, and Social Science Occupations (SOC major group)
|19-4000 |Life, Physical and Social Science Technicians (SOC minor group)&lt;br /&gt;
|19-4050 |Nuclear Technicians (SOC broad occupation) 19-4051 Nuclear Technicians (SOC detailed occupation)|&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In the O*NET-SOC taxonomy, an occupation that is directly adopted from the SOC system is assigned the six-digit SOC code, along with a .00 extension. If directly adopted from the SOC, the SOC title and definition are also used. Hereafter, these are referred to as SOC-level occupations.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If the O*NET-SOC occupation is more detailed than the original SOC detailed occupation, it is assigned the six-digit SOC code from which it originated, along with a two-digit extension starting with .01, then .02, .03 and so on, depending on the number of detailed O*NET-SOC occupations linked to the particular SOC detailed occupation.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For example, Nuclear Technicians is a SOC detailed occupation to which two detailed O*NET-SOC occupations are linked. See the occupational codes and titles for this example below.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;19-4051.00 Nuclear Technicians (SOC-level)
19-4051.01 Nuclear Equipment Operation Technicians
(detailed O*NET-SOC occupation)
19-4051.02 Nuclear Monitoring Technicians
(detailed O*NET-SOC occupation)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Both 19-4051.01 Nuclear Equipment Operation Technicians and 19-4051.02 Nuclear Monitoring Technicians are data-level occupations in the taxonomy. Data-level occupations are those for which the O*NET program collects data from job incumbents, occupational experts, and occupational analysts on a wide variety of variables and scales, such as occupational characteristics and worker requirements drawn from the &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.onetcenter.org/content.html&#34;&gt;O*NET Content Model&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In the example above, the two detailed O*NET-SOC occupations, 19-4051.01 Nuclear Equipment Operation Technicians and 19-4051.02 Nuclear Monitoring Technicians, are data- level occupations, whereas the SOC detailed occupation, 19-4051.00 Nuclear Technicians, is not an O*NET data-level occupation. “&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&#34;use-of-the-o-net-soc&#34;&gt;Use of the O*Net SOC&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As a taxonomy of occupation titles and groupings, the O*Net SOC provides a solid framework that is not only supported and used within the government (for recruiting and classification), but mandated to some extent as the reporting structure for compliance initiatives within the Department of Labor.  Given the number of federal contractors and scope of compliance and regulatory authority, any model system will at some point require a cross-walk as a minimum when used in practice.  As a practical tool for job seekers, this taxonomy leaves much to be desired. For instance, of the 1110 detailed job classification titles, 136 have no data associated with them being either too specific, marginal or “residual” in nature.  Functionally, having 136 titles unrelated to data causes issues within a system of operation.  Additionally, the numbering system lacks sufficient scalability to address job changes and increasing specificity that continues to creep into the marketplace.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Fundamentally, the O*Net SOC provides a sound foundation upon which a taxonomy may be constructed for defining and organizing job categories and to some extent job titles.  Additional layers of complexity arise, however as the full O*Net Content Model is unveiled.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;o-net-content-model&#34;&gt;O*Net Content Model&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Content Model is both the conceptual foundation of O*Net, and the framework by which detail is associated with job titles.  The Content Model is divided along a central axis that splits data sets between worker orientation and job-orientation.  Worker orientation characteristics and requirements include generalized abilities, interests, values, styles, skills, knowledge, education, experience, training, licensing and entry requirements.  This content recognizes the vast majority of information that comes into play in the typical hiring and selection process.  The flip-side of the model, “job-oriented” characteristics and requirements focuses on occupational, workforce and occupation-specific tasks, tools, technology, trends, and projections coupled with statements of work activities, work and organizational context.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;By dividing classification between worker-oriented and job-oriented, the O*Net system identifies tacitly the key challenge in HR transactions:  the gap between worker needs, attributes and interests, and actual job requirements.  The challenge in HR transactions (especially hire and promotion) is to match optimal “worker-characteristics” with occupational requirements. A useful job model must be capable of creating associations between these two tensions.  The second “division” of characteristics in the O*Net Content Model rests between what is termed as “Cross-Occupation” requirements and “Occupation-Specific” requirements.  Worker Characteristics and Occupational Requirements align with the Cross-Occupation threshold, while “Experience Requirements” and “Occupation-Specific” information balance the Occupation Specific orientation.  In the visual model, O*Net adds “Worker Requirements” and “Workforce Characteristics” to create a central axis.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;demystifying-the-o-net-content-model&#34;&gt;Demystifying the O*Net Content Model&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The greatest barrier to wide commercial adoption of the O*Net model is its complexity, and the lack of ability to appropriately align the measurable worker characteristics with identifiable occupational requirements.  The issue in creating efficiencies within the transactional process is finding an effective balance between detail and simplicity.   Job descriptions or definitions that are too simple attract too many applicants and create administrative and regulatory nightmares for the business, while frustrating job seekers who become lost in a pile of resumes.  Too much detail leads to few candidates and the possibility of no qualified candidates, creating vacancies in critical business functions.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This model also provides limited insight into how competencies combine to facilitate the translation of competencies across job types and industries. At its core, the O*Net model is mechanistic in its approach to defining occupational requirements.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Reviewing the detailed taxonomy created for the O*Net Content Model, it becomes apparent that the content is structured in the form of a simple outline: [ #.A.#.a.# ].  Each of the six categories is described as an Element and assigned an Element ID, with the heading element given a single Numeric to begin numbering from 1 - 6 as follows:  1 Worker Characteristics;  2 Worker Requirements;  3 Experience Requirements; 4 Occupational Requirements;  Occupation-Specific Information; and 6 Workforce Characteristics.   The final two have little specificity at all suggesting that either the available content is incomplete, or someone just got tired and decided to stop creating classification titles and descriptions after 4.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Only one of the six Elements has additional associated content formatted with an ID code:  Element 4 associates each Element ID with “General Work Activities (GWA)” and “Detailed Work Activities (DWA).”  Interestingly, the logical relationships created through the mapped classifications provide a useful foundation for addressing the critical gaps in the system, and a rudimentary structure for a simple but usable competency taxonomy.  Unfortunately, the numbering system utilized is rife with issues due to its paper-based nomenclature.  When adjusted, however, the possibilities for a viable decision framework become apparent.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&#34;understanding-fit&#34;&gt;Understanding Fit&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So how do we effectively create a structure that opens the doors of possibility for a functional taxonomy to address the inherent complexities and inefficiencies of HR transactions, most notably the Hire?  And how do we link such a structure to requisite training content to establish a pathway by which an individual can move from any present state to any future state? The Department of Education developed a classification system in 1980 to address the variance between degree and academic program offerings.  This structure is known as the Classification of Instructional Programs (CIP).  According to DoE, the CIP is described as follows, “The Classification of Instructional Programs (CIP) provides a taxonomic scheme that supports the accurate tracking and reporting of fields of study and program completions activity. CIP was originally developed by the U.S. Department of Education&amp;rsquo;s National Center for Education Statistics (NCES) in 1980, with revisions occurring in 1985, 1990, and 2000. For information about these early revisions to the CIP, click here or access specific links to historical versions from the resources page. For information about versions after CIP 2000, click the &amp;lsquo;change year&amp;rsquo; link on this site to see the available versions.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A cross walk between the O*NET database and CIP database is readily available, though linkages occur only at the SOC level and not deeper within the competency framework.  In order to develop a system that would link to both of these national standards, while allowing for near infinite expansion, a new code - one beyond the existing structure must be developed - and I would submit must be open-source. At the heart of the STEM Type and CCFIT model (and indeed within the newest iterations of our Military Friendly surveys) lies the basis of this newly envisioned taxonomy structure along with an interactive framework that allows for complete customization of the linkages to permit continuous improvement in the quality of the matching algorithm and competency linkages as the system is used over time.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For those of you interested in partnering in this journey  - a journey I hope will lead to the birth of a new understanding of career opportunities I, as always, invite thoughts, insights and comments!&lt;/p&gt;


&lt;p class=&#34;center&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;a href=&#34;http://blockchain.redcell.ai&#34; class=&#34;button __download-link&#34;&gt;Try the Demo!&lt;/a&gt;

  &amp;nbsp;
  &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/getinsomnia/insomnia/releases/vhire-process&#34;
     class=&#34;button button--no-outline&#34;
     target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;
    View on GitHub
  &lt;/a&gt;
  
&lt;/p&gt;








            </description>
        </item>
        
        <item>
            <title>Texting has paved the way to AI in HR</title>
            <link>https://redcelltalent.com/blog/texting-artificial-intelligence-human-resources/</link>
            <pubDate>
                Wed, 15 Nov 2017 10:17:00 -0700
            </pubDate>
            
            <guid>https://redcelltalent.com/blog/texting-artificial-intelligence-human-resources/</guid>
            <description>
                


&lt;h1 id=&#34;texting-has-paved-the-way-for-artificial-intelligence-and-hr-should-get-on-board&#34;&gt;Texting has paved the way for artificial intelligence, and HR should get on board.&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Texting isn’t new by any stretch of the imagination. As a communication medium that has been around for more than 20 years, it has just begun to hit its stride in the past few years. Widespread, generally free, real-time and with incredible reach, texting and messaging has become a central component if not a driving force in human interaction.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But the real question … do you really know who or what you are talking to? The separation between human communication and the familiarity and trust placed on what is effectively anonymous written communication has narrowed to the point that conditions are now ideal for the introduction and mass adoption of artificial intelligence driven digital communications.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;texting-is-pervasive&#34;&gt;Texting is pervasive.&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;97% of americans text or message at least once a day &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.pewinternet.org/2015/04/01/us-smartphone-use-in-2015/&#34;&gt;Pew Research Center&lt;/a&gt; while people worldwide will send 8.3 Trillion messages this year … nearly 16 million messages per minute, making it the most common cell phone activity by far. 55% of heavy text message users (50+ per day) would rather receive a text than a phone call &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.pewinternet.org/2011/09/19/americans-and-text-messaging/&#34;&gt;Pew Research Center&lt;/a&gt;.  In all of this, how easy is it really to differentiate between a human and machine at the other end of the conversation? In five years or less, you may not be able to tell the difference.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Similarly, the candidate callback program is nothing new. With the growth of technology, candidate callbacks began to first decline in the mid ‘90’s, despite evidence of their efficacy. The reason? Volume. With the advent of internet and digital applications, it is simply unreasonable to call all candidates back, even after an interview and especially if they are not selected.  Or is it?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The majority of callback programs are vehemently disliked by the recruiting staff … regardless of what they may claim in team discussions. But let&amp;rsquo;s have a look at the numbers. In the U.S. we ended 2017 with around 5.5 million hires per month and 5.2 million separations. &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.bls.gov/news.release/pdf/jolts.pdf&#34;&gt;Read the Labor Report&lt;/a&gt; We&amp;rsquo;ll use Glassdoor&amp;rsquo;s 250 resumes per job average as well as their estimation that only 2% are called in for an interview. Those number suggest that there every month there are about 1.375 Billion applications submitted (people obviously apply to more than one job). Of those, around 275 Million are invited for an interview and 5.5 Million are hired.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If we translate that for the average midsize company that hires say 1,000 employees per year, with a team of 5 recruiters, that equals around 5 hours per workday of call time if you were to reach back out to just the applicants that interviewed.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So this brings us to the first role of artificial intelligence in HR. Much of current discusison around AI in HR is focused on selection … but few hiring managers appear to be ready to embrace AI in their talent selection process, given some of the unknowns regarding selection bias and regulatory oversight. Candidate callbacks, then become a prime avenue for both improved outcomes and cost savings. In the emerging era of value-based service, this is the kind of use-case for which HR professionals have been searching.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And the world is ready for it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;people-are-tuning-in-to-communications-technologies-at-an-ever-expanding-level&#34;&gt;People are tuning in to communications technologies at an ever-expanding level.&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Some recent indicators:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Nearly 20 million of the 225 million Twitter users follow 60 or more Twitter accounts and nearly 2 million follow more than 500 accounts.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;There are more than 800 million people now signed up for the social network Facebook; they spend 700 billion minutes using Facebook each month, and they install more than 20 million apps every day.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Facebook users had uploaded more than 100 billion photos by mid-2011.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;YouTube users upload 60 hours of video per minute and they triggered more than 1 trillion playbacks in 2011 – roughly 140 video views per person on earth.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;What if we tap into the power of texting … mobile communication and AI … to bring efficacy to applicant and candidate communications. We have at our disposal, not just messaging, but video, voice, alerts, prompts, vibrations … and so much more … all customizable for a specific candidate at a specific time, location and for a specific purpose. AI driven communications do not need to be inhuman at all, rather, AI techniques provide an opportunity to enhance HR communications both before and after the hire.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Undoubtedly, regulation has slowed the adoption of social strategies in HR, but more than federal and state regulation is a simpler lack of understanding of mobile communication options. Opt-ins, alerts, and push notifications are common functions of messaging applications, as is anonymity and data security. Notifications, prompts or even targeted communications can take advantage of peer to peer (device to device) communications or be delivered without revealing sensitive information about the candidate, and delivered only to the party directed.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The challenge has been implementing these types of solutions at scale and with a high degree of customization and responsiveness. Programmatic solutions combined with deep learning techniques provide powerful options for recruites and HR to stay and get back in touch via the mobile world.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;you-re-probably-missing-huge-amounts-of-meaningful-and-available-data&#34;&gt;You&amp;rsquo;re probably missing huge amounts of meaningful and available data&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Behind the huge volume of HR-relevant information available online sits an even broader data pool. Piecing together the different sites a candidate is visiting combined (including the company&amp;rsquo;s website) with offline data (like the application), as well as demographic and geographic details, can present a far richer picture for recruiters in terms of what information an individual candidate might find most useful at each stage during their recruiting and onboarding journey. As an efficient technology, programmatic has proved itself adept at translating data from multiple sources into actionable insights, getting the right info to the right individual more quickly, while maintaining appropriate levels of privacy.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;While the benefits of programmatic advertising in recruiting are becoming clearer, the issue of maintaining regulatory compliance remains all-important.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There are longstanding Labor guidelines in place that digital marketers must observe in all recruiting engagement. However, the Network Advertising Initiative went further on programmatic, issuing specific guidance to help advertisers succeed in this environment. This includes a usage and consent framework for data derived from sensitive sources, as well as all other data sources, including data collected by publishers.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;we-can-augment-your-efforts-to-get-you-up-to-speed-quickly&#34;&gt;We can Augment your efforts to get you up to speed quickly&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Our process is simple from an execution standpoint. We partner with recruiters and HR professionals to craft and execute communication &amp;ldquo;prescriptions&amp;rdquo;. Candidate agreement is obtained up-front, along with their preferred contact methods, frequency and restrictions. These prescribed conversations can begin as soon as the candidate leaves the website, or be tied to events such as the interview and can include a vast variety of alerts, notices and communications across platforms to optimize applicant nurturing and talent management, and to facilitate eventual onboarding, or an ongoing relationship for when a suitable job is open.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Modern marketing technologies have never been a more powerful support for human resources, and with careful management, can help cut through the clutter of bad data and improve candidate and employee engagement.&lt;/p&gt;


&lt;p class=&#34;center&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;a href=&#34;http://blockchain.redcell.ai&#34; class=&#34;button __download-link&#34;&gt;Try the Demo!&lt;/a&gt;

  &amp;nbsp;
  &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/getinsomnia/insomnia/releases/vtexting-artificial-intelligence-human-resources&#34;
     class=&#34;button button--no-outline&#34;
     target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;
    View on GitHub
  &lt;/a&gt;
  
&lt;/p&gt;








            </description>
        </item>
        
        <item>
            <title>Our AI wrote an article for military job seekers.</title>
            <link>https://redcelltalent.com/blog/article-artificial-intelligence/</link>
            <pubDate>
                Sat, 21 Oct 2017 22:01:22 -0700
            </pubDate>
            
            <guid>https://redcelltalent.com/blog/article-artificial-intelligence/</guid>
            <description>
                


&lt;h1 id=&#34;we-fed-15-years-of-gi-jobs-magazine-articles-to-our-artificial-intelligence-and-it-wrote-an-article-just-for-you&#34;&gt;We fed 15 years of GI Jobs Magazine articles to our artificial intelligence and it wrote an article just for you:&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You’ve undoubtedly been reading a great deal about the rise of Artificial Intelligence, and admittedly, what we’ve done here is nothing particularly new or novel, but the results are interesting depending on how deep you want to read into the potential meaning of the text.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A couple of the technical specs for those that are interested:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;Total Sentences:  1,170,479
Iterations: 35
Epochs per iteration: 3-10
Language: Python
ML Libraries: Tensorflow, Keras
Hours of Training: 53+ (yeah we just used our local machines)
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;a-few-thoughts-about-the-results&#34;&gt;A few thoughts about the results:&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Humans don’t start their thinking from scratch every second. As you read this article, you understand each word based on your understanding of previous words. You don’t throw everything away and start thinking from scratch again. Your thoughts have persistence.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Traditional neural networks can’t do this, and it seems like a major shortcoming. For example, imagine you want to classify what kind of event is happening at every point in a movie. It’s unclear how a traditional neural network could use its reasoning about previous events in the film to inform later ones.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Recurrent neural networks (RNN) address this issue. They are networks with loops in them, allowing information to persist. RNNs have been used to address a variety of problems: speech recognition, language modeling, translation, image captioning … and yes even article writing like we’ve done here.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Essential to these successes is the use of Long Short Term Memory (LSTM) networks which are a very special kind of recurrent neural network that work, for many tasks, much better than the standard RNNs. Almost all exciting results based on recurrent neural networks are achieved with them.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To generate any kind of meaningful text takes a large volume of data, considerable tuning, and much more computing time than we expected (hello 48 hour computations?!). The results, in addition to some really insightful sentences, provide some interesting insights into a 15 year dialogue with military transitioners regarding their transition. A few prompts as you read the passage generated by our AI:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;What do you think of the choice of title and subtitle?
What connections are made between schools, companies and military commands?
The AI created a couple of words, any thoughts about their meaning?
In the end, the AI suggests a link to a post, but did not supply one =(  - So we added our own post from one of our sponsors.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Without further ado …. Enjoy the article, and if you’d like to talk to our AI, Gunny Jobs is available on Facebook Messenger and Twitter.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;-------
-------

# Cyber Security Is In Huge Demand

&amp;gt; programs looking for military experience and getting the most out of providing the military opportunity. 

Services for veterans, are hot, and I don’t see an end to the value a small support has to a feeling your service to a nation matters to the company and what was served for provides the support and experience in the marketing and similar terms that are used on the resume. The company can see your work in the working to be four weekends of work to be considerable amount of research and of waits before you get to their program. Businesses understand that maybe you worked too many considerations for a position and the first interview and are seeking better ways when you can engage to make it happen.

We should make the student the corporation and every recruiter with a life perspective that covers the entire military experience. But whether they find the time for a program in the company or have the experience to contract a resume service or contract to a school a way of considering a person, because they seem to consider the battles of the military candidate.  Great successful may be found in contracts between the campus and the company to find a time to consider the application esuaration with which you ensure employment.

That promise was expanded to include the resume to the transition and to filling any competing gaps between the community and the company in a few states. The same collaboration is needed to address the stressful change to employment between leadership in the company and the commanders. The make transition to community possible is a position for advisors to maintaining a personal good, or to get the company promoted. You are in the company and the company in the students allows the military friendly community to franchise your veteran stepnation to check your strategy and support.

After receiving your information, these verbal fields are easy to battle owners of the military experience record. What you have done to assist the job fit needs to enlarge in the pertations and to the financial benefit of the military student. Once the veteran student starts to receive the most stailory step to the promise of careers, they make a want to a company for computer interns. On close of the post is the program with the student performance that requirements can work to a career and a program and you don’t have stop your term of military service.


-------
-------
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;a-possible-interpretation&#34;&gt;A possible interpretation&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Those of you reading this, may have your own take on what is being said. Having spent a number of years in ancient language translation, I somehow feel uniquely qualified to offer a summary. Here’s my thoughts of each paragraph … we would love to hear yours:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Programs for veteran transition are popular because companies realize that veterans are spending far too much time trying to figure out how they fit into civilian jobs. Many companies are trying to find a solution that works.
What we should do, is flip the script and train companies and recruiters on what military experience really means. But companies likely don’t have the time or interest to invest in training or outsourcing reliable and effective services … even though they are quick to recognize that veterans may be affected by combat experience.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;One solution is for Colleges and Companies to partner to ensure that military transition leads to employment.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This partnership needs to expand to include resume translation support and to identify gaps that may exist between what a company offers and what it’s surrounding community offers. (ie. the community is potentially as important as the job in ensuring a successful transition)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The same type of collaboration (between companies and schools) is needed between companies and military commands, especially because advisors often have competing agendas: doing what is best for the individual or best for the company PR goals.
Communities with best practices should be “franchised” to replicate their success.
Verbal interviews are important in addressing bias against mis-understandings of military experience. Skills gained in military service should have more weight in determining civilian pay. Once veteran students understand their fit, they can take positive steps toward high demand careers and they begin to realize the value of internships.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Optimal opportunities would allow the service member to begin their transition while in the military.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’d love to see your interpretation … is the AI on the right track?&lt;/p&gt;


&lt;p class=&#34;center&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;a href=&#34;http://blockchain.redcell.ai&#34; class=&#34;button __download-link&#34;&gt;Try the Demo!&lt;/a&gt;

  &amp;nbsp;
  &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/getinsomnia/insomnia/releases/varticle-artificial-intelligence&#34;
     class=&#34;button button--no-outline&#34;
     target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;
    View on GitHub
  &lt;/a&gt;
  
&lt;/p&gt;








            </description>
        </item>
        
        <item>
            <title>Eliminating Bias and Google&#39;s Jobs API</title>
            <link>https://redcelltalent.com/blog/google-job-api-bias/</link>
            <pubDate>
                Thu, 28 Sep 2017 00:00:00 +0000
            </pubDate>
            
            <guid>https://redcelltalent.com/blog/google-job-api-bias/</guid>
            <description>
                


&lt;h1 id=&#34;google-just-launched-their-cloud-jobs-api-but-will-it-be-biased-against-military-job-seekers&#34;&gt;Google just launched their Cloud Jobs API - but will it be biased against military job seekers?&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“At the heart of Cloud Jobs API, there are two main proprietary ontologies that encode knowledge about occupations and skills, as well as relational models between these ontologies… The occupational ontology, an enhanced evolution of O*NET Standard Occupational Classification…”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We’ve recently applied to take part in the beta release of the Google Cloud Jobs API and while we await response from google I read the line above with great interest and a little bit of trepidation. Why the hesitance you ask? Admittedly, I’m a fan of google cloud services and products - I’ve developed apps on top of firebase, Gunny Jobs is built on Google’s DialogFlow NLP interface, and most recently I’ve been building predictive AI models to help military transition to civilian jobs based with Google’s Tensorflow and Machine Learning engine.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’m hesitant because I’ve worked with the O*Net model for years and believe very strongly that it is highly biased against military skills … and it does a very poor job of helping military translate their skills to civilian life and jobs.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;That being said, I recognize that Google (according to their very limited public documentation) is primarily using O*Net as an occupation ontology (a set of categories), net necessarily as a skill ontology. The genesis of their skill ontology is more opaque, “The skill ontology defines and organizes around 50,000 hard and soft skills with different types of relationships such as is_a, related_to, etc.” In Google’s model, occupations are grouped by the similarity of their skill distributions. All of this makes perfect sense.  A person’s employability is shaped by their ability to perform specific skills at a specified level of competence.  For a more indepth diatribe on the topic, feel free to read one or several of my earlier essays on the topic.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I freely embrace the concept of viewing a job applicant according to a set of competencies (skills proven at a specific level of ability) … comparing this set of competencies to that of a job listing and identifying fit. I’ve used the same type of approach to not only identify skill fit but also to identify gaps in skills for the purpose of creating on-demand skill training.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;so-if-i-agree-with-the-approach-why-the-hesitance&#34;&gt;So, if I agree with the approach … why the hesitance?&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I hesitate to fully embrace the Google Job model because if they are working from O*Net - O*Net uses a bridge to connect occupations in their ontology with Military Occupations in a separate database. Furthermore, the Department of Defense neither provides, nor categorizes military skills using the same skill database as the Department of Labor.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Case in point - there is no standardization of skill training for the military medic across all branches of service. The National Council of State Boards of Nursing (NCSBN) recently revised their analysis of military medic to RN training equivalence and it doesn’t take you long to discover two obvious points: 1. There’s no easy way for a medic to translate their skills, and 2. There’s no way a single job description will ever list all the skill requirements that actually go into an occupation.  The O*Net skill translator … and for the most part every MOS to Civilian translator does a really poor job of translation, and in fact biases against military training … that is to say, if you review equivalence and job recommendation across military to civilian job recommendations you find that military occupations are ALWAYS correlated with more junior civilian occupations. Military transitioners are chronically underemployed upon exit … they are underemployed because the very fabric upon which civilian occupations rest is systematically biased against the skills they gained during their military service.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I had been hoping for better when Google announced their product in June … with this next phase and more information, I am no longer hopeful for the viability of Google’s platform or approach as an answer for military in transition. I will, however, keep you read in on what we discover if we are invited into the beta program … in which case we will be building in a better translational model.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Of course … skill set matching without testing and evidence … no matter how good the natural language processing is … how valuable is that really?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;are-there-alternatives-i-believe-so&#34;&gt;Are there alternatives?  I believe so.&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you recall, I recently announced the development of our Military job AI project titled “Gunny Jobs.” Part of this project combines with our veteran survey, that captures information about prior service, education level, demographics, location and job … and whether or not they like who they are working for and what they are doing.  There are adjustments to be made for sure, and we need more data as our model is still only inclusive of a 722 x 38 x 83 model (MOS, Major, Occupation). I believe that until such a time as an unbiased model is available, the best approach is to identify employers that do the best job in selection, hiring, promoting and engaging military veterans in jobs they can succeed in and enjoy. By identifying these critical pathways, we can provide useful guidance to transitioning military.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;What do we need? More data =) If you are a veteran I encourage you to &lt;strong&gt;#JointheRanks&lt;/strong&gt;  - we’ll be distributing survey links … if you’re currently employed, ask your HR officer to contact Redcell to request our proprietary Employee Survey - or for schools, our Student Survey. All the data from these surveys is being used to feed our AI model … to help build a job search tool that recognizes the real value of military service.&lt;/p&gt;


&lt;p class=&#34;center&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;a href=&#34;http://blockchain.redcell.ai&#34; class=&#34;button __download-link&#34;&gt;Try the Demo!&lt;/a&gt;

  &amp;nbsp;
  &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/getinsomnia/insomnia/releases/vgoogle-job-api-bias&#34;
     class=&#34;button button--no-outline&#34;
     target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;
    View on GitHub
  &lt;/a&gt;
  
&lt;/p&gt;








            </description>
        </item>
        
        <item>
            <title>Why we built the first AI for military in transition</title>
            <link>https://redcelltalent.com/blog/first-ai-job-search/</link>
            <pubDate>
                Tue, 19 Sep 2017 22:01:22 -0700
            </pubDate>
            
            <guid>https://redcelltalent.com/blog/first-ai-job-search/</guid>
            <description>
                


&lt;h1 id=&#34;why-we-built-the-first-a-i-for-military-in-transition&#34;&gt;Why we built the first A.I. for military in transition&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.facebook.com/gunnyjobs/&#34;&gt;Talk to Gunny Jobs&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;#FillTheTrough&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There are more than 42,000 non-profits with a military and veteran community focus, more than 14,000 OJT programs and 36,000 education programs in total eligible to receive GI Bill funds. Military Transition Assistance Programs (TAP) are mandatory for transitioning veterans. None of this takes into account the millions of individuals investing personally in assisting veterans during their transition to civilian life.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The result: a record-low unemployment rate of 5.1 percent for Post-911 veterans in 2016 … a drop from the 2011 high of 12.1 percent.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;So …. Mission accomplished!?&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Perhaps not so much. Lagging indicators suggest that employment satisfaction is a considerable issue, with 44 percent of veterans leaving their new civilian job within the first year. While a number of research studies suggest that veterans eventually earn more than their non-veteran peers there is a recognized lag of time before this the case. That is, there appears to be a period of time between immediate exit from military service and the point at which veterans begin to exceed their non-veteran peers in term of civilian earnings. Newer research is only now emerging on Post-911 veterans, but seems to reinforce these findings.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Let’s call it the Trough of Veteran Income Inequality and Dissatisfaction. The Chaplain in me suggests perhaps the “slough of despond” as an equally apt term, but that will only lead to unintended allegory. So I’ll stick with a very DoD acronym: TVIID or perhaps simply, “The Trough.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As a transitioning veteran research suggests that you’ve likely found yourself in “The Trough” upon exiting military service: making less than you did or disillusioned by the role you’re in, or both. Research also suggests that this trough not only exists today, but is pretty much a standard economic structure of the military transition experience.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;One would think that with millions of people and more than 80,000 programs dedicated to veteran success in civilian life that we would have solved this issue by new … or at least started to fill in the trough. There’s a catchy hashtag #FillTheTrough! But I digress as we were talking about A.I.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For a number of years, we’ve had this dream of connecting military in transition with people like them … those that followed similar career paths in the hope that this sort of connection would lead to an escape velocity that would speed veterans toward civilian success and avoid “The Trough.” Mathematically and logically, this doesn’t really play out as logic is about the study of consequence and mathematics is really about proving general statements. In other words, you can’t prove a general assertion from a single observation.  What you can do is capture a preponderance of specific observations together to derive a general principle, from which you can make a logical statement.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;More simply put:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;[NOT VALID]  A recently separated infantry soldier tells an active duty soldier of the same rank that they love shoveling dirt … therefore all infantry will love shoveling dirt. [NOT VALID]

[VALID] Ten million separated infantry soldiers enjoy shoveling dirt after transition… therefore other infantry will enjoy shoveling dirt after separation. [VALID]
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This example, of course, is purely fictional&amp;hellip; as we all know that infantry don’t enjoy anything.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It does highlight the challenges of the vast majority of 1:1 programs and mentoring initiatives, and even the challenge TAP facilitators face.  One person’s experience … even ten million experiences&amp;hellip; don’t address the tens of thousands of viable options that may exist, and one person’s personal experiences may not be a fit at all.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Enter artificial intelligence. Artificial intelligence is fairly simple conceptually, but brutally challenging mathematically. A neural network, or deep learning algorithm takes an input, processes that through a number of “hidden layer” calculations and produces an output. This is illustrated by the chart below of a proposed design for a facial recognition algorithm.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Recent advances in both open source and affordable A.I. platforms has opened the door wide to the use of deep learning for a number of applications. Over the past few years, we have developed connections between the input - military occupation and the output - satisfaction in a given civilian career.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Yes, pretty cool … but we’re still a long way from something that is truly predictive. What we lack is training … or basically … more data in the model to generate more accurate outcomes. While building this network out, we thought about different options for the human interface and decided to stick with the A.I. motif by designing a chatbot interface that could process natural language.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Enter Gunny Jobs&lt;/em&gt;. Gunny’s current knowledge set includes:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;8,564 military occupations including their codes and titles. 
1105 civilian occupations with their occupational codes and an average of 30 alternatives
2318 Majors and Curriculum Codes
Military Pay Rates and Ranks
Military Branches
A smattering of snarky conversation
Natural Language Processing
Cool hidden features that you may never find
Many more features to come
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;His feature set, however, is still very nascent. Currently Gunny can chat [there are lots of hidden easter eggs in his conversational repertoire], Gunny plays a simple military occupation (MOS) guessing game that takes in new inputs. (who knows where vets will take that one), and he can perform a job search based on your MOS. So we’re nowhere near the predictive capabilities that we’re developing, but as it was suggested to a colleague … “you couldn’t talk when you were a day old … so Gunny’s already ahead of you!”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;With so much choice … so many options … veterans generally fall into “The Trough” because of the lack of real decision support tools that deliver meaningful results based on data. Eventually, we hope that Gunny Jobs can help address some of the gap … perhaps fill in a bit of the The Trough by consuming those millions of data inputs and over time delivering smarter outputs and recommendations. We’ve been collecting inputs on veteran employee and student satisfaction in their jobs and their majors for over a year now. While the progress is slow, we intend to integrate that data collection effort directly into Gunny Jobs.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The beauty is that this technology is capable of not only integrating with Facebook Messenger as it already does, but also with the Google Assistant, Alexa, Cortana, Slack, Line, Skype, Vibe and numerous other platforms where servicemembers are. As artificial intelligence, Gunny Jobs does not sleep, his cloud-based core is always available … and he’s even available to augment the work of the millions of people who interact.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We don’t intend for Gunny Jobs to replace transition staff … rather we hope that the collective voice of veterans will begin to compile a highly meaningful tool to #FillTheTrough for veterans in transition.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you want to find Gunny Jobs:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Start a conversation with Gunny Jobs on Facebook Messenger.
Start a conversation with Gunny Jobs on Twitter @GunnyJobs&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Very soon you’ll also be able ask the google assistant: “Hey Google, Talk to Gunny Jobs.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;#FillTheTrough&lt;/p&gt;


&lt;p class=&#34;center&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;a href=&#34;http://blockchain.redcell.ai&#34; class=&#34;button __download-link&#34;&gt;Try the Demo!&lt;/a&gt;

  &amp;nbsp;
  &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/getinsomnia/insomnia/releases/vfirst-ai-job-search&#34;
     class=&#34;button button--no-outline&#34;
     target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;
    View on GitHub
  &lt;/a&gt;
  
&lt;/p&gt;








            </description>
        </item>
        
        <item>
            <title>How you can get to the next 2.0 version of yourself.</title>
            <link>https://redcelltalent.com/blog/proud-hungry-driven/</link>
            <pubDate>
                Mon, 14 Aug 2017 22:01:22 -0700
            </pubDate>
            
            <guid>https://redcelltalent.com/blog/proud-hungry-driven/</guid>
            <description>
                


&lt;h1 id=&#34;proud-hungry-driven-phd&#34;&gt;PROUD, HUNGRY, DRIVEN (PHD)&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;how-can-you-get-to-the-next-2-0-3-0-version-of-yourself&#34;&gt;How can you get to the next 2.0, 3.0 version of yourself.&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“I want Robert Morris to be part of the military transition pipeline - from wearing the uniform and having a purpose to not wearing the uniform and having a purpose.”
&lt;em&gt;Dr. Christopher Howard, 8th President of Robert Morris University&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When is the last time you had a conversation that changed you for the better? When was the last time you connected with a person willing to share of themselves, and what they shared made a difference? Who was the last person who took nothing from you, gave you everything they had in the moment of that exchange, and left you better for having met you?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My conversation with Dr. Christopher Howard, the eighth president of Robert Morris University in Pennsylvania and an Air Force veteran, was one of those moments … because he is one of those people. You can “google” his background, and I encourage you to do so, and you will undoubtedly be as impressed as I was in reading about his accomplishments, as we should be. But if all you are is impressed … or perhaps a little jealous, then you are missing something important and rare.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It is my privilege to share my brief moments with Howard, moments that filled the time and space of our conversation entirely; and it is my hope to share with you the heart he opened to me in a way that will make a difference as you tackle the challenge of your military transition.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;One of the most challenging things to do is to follow in the steps of another, especially someone who has accomplished far more than the average person. What I hoped to accomplish in speaking with Howard was to seek his answers to two specific questions, and in so doing to somehow deconstruct the path he took so that others might be able to follow: What should you look for in yourself? What should you look for in an institution of higher learning?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&#34;what-should-you-look-for-in-yourself&#34;&gt;WHAT SHOULD YOU LOOK FOR IN YOURSELF&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Before we dive in, we have some ground-laying work to do beginning with my first takeaway: “Forgive yourself.” We’ll come back to this notion because Howard concluded our conversation with this critical piece of advice that I believe belongs here at the beginning. Your military career is coming to an end. Perhaps you achieved everything you wanted. More than likely there is something more that you wish you could have achieved: if not rank, then an assignment; if not an assignment, perhaps a skill or degree; or honor, or award, or something that someone else managed to accomplish that you did not.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Start with forgiveness, for not reaching whatever goals you had hoped to achieve to date … and then ask yourself, “What do you want to do?” and “Who do you want to be?”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“Stop and reflect about what you want, otherwise you’re a hammer and everything looks like a nail.” - Dr. Christopher Howard&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Howard has a way of simplifying and clarifying challenging topics and concepts, of cutting to the heart of a matter in a way that can be recalled and shared, and an uncanny ability to visualize what he is saying. He spoke of military transition to civilian life as a venn diagram. For those of us who have been out of school for awhile, that is essentially two or more overlapping circles - in this case representing what you do in the military and what you need to do outside. “About 80 percent of it comes over … and there’s 20 percent that’s a little different: your mindset, how suasion works, how authority works…”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In other words, there is a tremendous amount of your military experience and the character that you’ve developed that not only translates, but is highly valued by civilian employers. Being able to perform the tasks of a job is a given, but eventually it will come down to, “integrity, being able to get things done, having a high emotional intelligence.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“What so many transitioners do when they transition is try to grab anything that’s out there … I’m not saying that people don’t have family situations of geographic preferences … but you have to stop and say what do I want? Otherwise you’re a hammer, and everything looks like a nail.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This mindset is why so many veterans find themselves in “vicious cycles” while their civilian peers seem to more easily find the paths that lead to success, which Howard describes as “virtuous cycles.” These virtuous cycles are not dissimilar from specialized military training pipelines, the most famous of which is the Navy SEAL team training pipeline. The difference is that civilian pipelines are rarely as clearly laid out.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;the-virtuous-cycle&#34;&gt;The Virtuous Cycle&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Howard was in eighth grade when he took his first steps toward the virtuous cycle that would eventually lead him from success to success from his military career through his academic career and then into his civilian career and beyond. He was a good student in middle school, but determined that he wanted to be more and set a goal of achieving A+ grades in all of his classes. That year he achieved his goal, “not because I was necessarily smarter than all the other kids, it was because I was determined to do so.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;He found that as he began to be more comfortable with himself, new opportunities and strengths began to reveal themselves. People in the military, for instance, begin to learn this and as they do, they develop a sense of agency, that if they do “A” … “B” will happen. Military training pushes individuals to reach competency standards across a wide range of skills with a sense of urgency. Veterans know about these training “pipelines,” and the longer the pipeline, the more specialized your capabilities for supporting the force. In the military there are always hand-offs between segments of the pipeline, along with proving points where what you have learned is tested in practice. In the civilian world, this rarely exists.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In civilian life, more responsibility is placed on the individual to choose the right major, the right teacher, an internship that leads to another internship or research project that leads to the right network. To be successful, and to tap into the pipelines that exist in the civilian world, veterans need to get three PhDs: A PhD in yourself, a PhD in the world around you, and a PhD in leadership.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;proud-hungry-driven-phd-1&#34;&gt;Proud, Hungry, Driven (PhD)&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“I hate when people get frustrated that they don’t have it all figured out when they step into it.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A PhD in yourself refers to the need to be self-aware … or as noted above, to know yourself and to be comfortable with yourself. Howard suggests that people who are comfortable with themselves, “focus on circles, not dots.” They set slightly broader goals, with the same sense of urgency of someone seeking to achieve a very specific goal. For instance, people who are self-aware may seek to “serve people in law enforcement” rather than to be the, “LAPD police chief” because “life is not VFR direct … ‘if you can see it, go fly to it’ … usually there’s some zigs and some zags.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Having a PhD in the world around you suggests that you are contextually aware. You understand that you are no longer in a military command or performing your military duty. You are aware that some of what makes you successful in the military overlaps, and some of it doesn’t. Finally, you should always be gaining a Ph.D in leadership by studying leaders in your field and outside of your field to discover what makes them effective and successful. Knowing yourself, and being honest about it, knowing your environment and being aware of your situation, and constantly learning from leaders will develop a sense of agency, and, “if something in your life is giving you agency, you will be successful.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For those who have not decided, or are still seeking advice on making the right choice in transition, Howard offers a very simple rubric:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;If you’re passionate about something, follow your passions. But understand that passion means willing to sacrifice.
If you’re not passionate about something, follow your interests, because if you’re interested, you probably are working a little harder to succeed.
If you’re not passionate or interested, follow your strengths, because while you have to deal with your shortcomings, usually people who are successful in life are doing things that play to their strengths.
If you’re not passionate or interested or good at something … keep your options open and do things that keep your options open.
Finally, all things being equal, do something around Science, Technology, Engineering and Math (STEM) because that’s going to create options.
Then, when all is said and done, forgive yourself for not being on one of the other rungs in the ladder.
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;what-should-you-look-for-in-an-institution&#34;&gt;WHAT SHOULD YOU LOOK FOR IN AN INSTITUTION?&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;One of the final questions I asked of Howard focused on his role and leadership plans as president of Robert Morris University (RMU) in Pennsylvania. As a veteran, one would expect him to have a well-defined strategy for building a solid program to support veteran students, and as a multi-year recipient of the Military Friendly® School designation, Robert Morris University should present solid ground for such a program to grow. Immediately he grasped the purpose of the Military Friendly® program, “You can hang your shingle and say you are military friendly, but the proof is in the outcomes. If a school isn’t putting their own skin in the game they aren’t serious.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Indeed, for institutions that are getting it right, they take seriously their responsibility for serving their veteran and military students. At RMU, they have long been creating pipelines for their veteran students, and as Dr. Howard notes, “Everyone wants to be Military Friendly® …. I want Robert Morris to be part of the transition pipeline, from wearing the uniform and having a purpose to not wearing the uniform and having a purpose.” Yet he is highly aware that building an effective pipeline doesn’t happen overnight, because a pipeline is more than just a series of identified options: “There are handoffs all along the pipeline … and there are also reach-downs into the pipeline.” He notes that RMU is committed to placing veteran students in internships or co-ops with other like-minded companies that value military experience.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;What became clear in our discussion is that veterans should view their choice of academic institution as part of their pipeline or virtuous cycle, rather than merely a place to land while they are figuring things out. By selecting academic institutions that understand their and their place in the transition process, veterans have a much greater likelihood of finding success in their civilian careers. The Military Friendly® Schools program is designed to assist transitioning military in identifying institutions whose pipeline is known, established, resourced and constantly improving. Suggestions for making your own evaluation include:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;How did they treat you in the interview?  You can see the earnestness of the person interviewing you - they either understand or they want to understand.
Does the school have a real infrastructure to support veterans? Do they have dedicated space, mentoring, financial counseling and career placement?
How do they handle the paperwork during the application process? According to a survey of more than a thousand veteran students, how a school approaches and handles paperwork is the key differentiator between a program that is real and one that is not.
How soon do they engage you in career discussion? Do they help you think through the selection of a major based on what your goals are, do they understand what you did in the military and how that may impact your career goals?
Is there a job waiting at graduation? What are their post-graduation employment outcomes, and do their job placements lead to jobs that are relevant for the major selected.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;closing-thoughts&#34;&gt;CLOSING THOUGHTS&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As the interview drew to a close, I could not help but consider the wealth of knowledge shared in such a brief period of time. I can only hope that I have faithfully transmitted his thoughts in a meaningful way. For me, one question remained: “How have you changed in your own transition from military to civilian life?”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;First, and without pause, he suggested that the better question for transitioners is what did not change: his unflinching belief in integrity. “The military is a special place &amp;hellip; your signature is your bond. You do the right thing because it is the right thing. I say what I do and do what I say … and I’ve retained my bearing and the seriousness of what we’re trying to do … the sense of urgency and integrity remain.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Howard’s thoughts about what has changed in his experience of civilian life I felt were some of his most prescient and important thoughts. “In the military there was a paradigm of leadership that was pretty narrow … you were expected to look a certain way, sound a certain way, walk and talk a certain way. In the civilian world you discover that leaders come in all different shapes and sizes. There are people who did not look like my conditioned view of leadership …. There are other paradigms of great leaders that look nothing like that … and yet they are great people who care deeply about mission and purpose.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Finally, finding the right fit is about coming to a place that respects what you’ve done in the military and that will help you get to the best 2.0, 3.0 version of you. The institution you choose should provide a great education for the profession you’ve chosen, and they should also give you the practical experience and exposure to the people who will help you get to the next level. If you decide to take a look at Robert Morris, or any of our Military Friendly® Schools, I recommend that you seek out the opportunity to talk with Howard or his counterpart, as the experience may well be the moment that sets you into the virtuous cycle that will lead to your success in civilian life.&lt;/p&gt;


&lt;p class=&#34;center&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;a href=&#34;http://blockchain.redcell.ai&#34; class=&#34;button __download-link&#34;&gt;Try the Demo!&lt;/a&gt;

  &amp;nbsp;
  &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/getinsomnia/insomnia/releases/vproud-hungry-driven&#34;
     class=&#34;button button--no-outline&#34;
     target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;
    View on GitHub
  &lt;/a&gt;
  
&lt;/p&gt;








            </description>
        </item>
        
        <item>
            <title></title>
            <link>https://redcelltalent.com/deploy-cloud-fabric/</link>
            <pubDate>
                Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000
            </pubDate>
            
            <guid>https://redcelltalent.com/deploy-cloud-fabric/</guid>
            <description>
                


&lt;h1 id=&#34;demo-blockchain-instructions-google-cloud&#34;&gt;Demo Blockchain Instructions - Google Cloud&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;spin-up-your-google-cloud-compute-instance&#34;&gt;Spin up your Google Cloud Compute Instance&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;```Ubuntu 1604-lts
2 CPU 20GB
Compute engine
Access your instance
SSH “remote access”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;## Install Pre-reqs  
[prerequisits](https://medium.com/google-cloud/deploy-fabcar-on-hyperledger-fabric-93c082c31b7a)

&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;sudo apt-get update
sudo apt-get -y upgrade
sudo apt-get install python&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;
## Install Go go1.9.x
[instructions](https://www.samclarke.com/installing-go-1-9-on-ubuntu-16-04/)  355MB
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;sudo add-apt-repository ppa:gophers/archive&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;sudo apt update&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;sudo apt-get install golang-1.9-go&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;echo &amp;ldquo;export PATH=\$PATH:/usr/lib/go-1.9/bin&amp;rdquo; &amp;gt;&amp;gt; ~/.profile&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;source ~/.profile&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;
## Install node
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;curl -sL &lt;a href=&#34;https://deb.nodesource.com/setup_8.x&#34;&gt;https://deb.nodesource.com/setup_8.x&lt;/a&gt; | sudo -E bash -&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;sudo apt-get install -y nodejs&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;sudo apt-get install -y build-essential&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;nodejs -v&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;npm -v&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;
## Install docker-ce
[instructions](https://docs.docker.com/install/linux/docker-ce/ubuntu/#extra-steps-for-aufs)
For UBUNTU - you need to remove the older docker.io
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;sudo apt-get remove docker docker-engine docker.io&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;sudo apt-get update&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;sudo apt-get install &lt;br /&gt;
    apt-transport-https &lt;br /&gt;
    ca-certificates &lt;br /&gt;
    curl &lt;br /&gt;
    software-properties-common&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;curl -fsSL &lt;a href=&#34;https://download.docker.com/linux/ubuntu/gpg&#34;&gt;https://download.docker.com/linux/ubuntu/gpg&lt;/a&gt; | sudo apt-key add -&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;sudo apt-key fingerprint 0EBFCD88&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;sudo add-apt-repository &lt;br /&gt;
   &amp;ldquo;deb [arch=amd64] &lt;a href=&#34;https://download.docker.com/linux/ubuntu&#34;&gt;https://download.docker.com/linux/ubuntu&lt;/a&gt; &lt;br /&gt;
   $(lsb_release -cs) &lt;br /&gt;
   stable&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;sudo apt-get update&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;sudo apt-get install docker-ce&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;sudo docker run hello-world&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;sudo groupadd docker&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;sudo usermod -aG docker $USER&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;sudo systemctl enable docker&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;docker &amp;ndash;version&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;docker run hello-world&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;You may need to close the shell and open a new one.

## Install docker-compose
[install](https://docs.docker.com/compose/install/#install-compose)
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;sudo curl -L &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/docker/compose/releases/download/1.19.0/docker-compose-`uname&#34;&gt;https://github.com/docker/compose/releases/download/1.19.0/docker-compose-`uname&lt;/a&gt; -s&lt;code&gt;-&lt;/code&gt;uname -m` -o /usr/local/bin/docker-compose&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;sudo chmod +x /usr/local/bin/docker-compose&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;docker-compose &amp;ndash;version&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;
## Install JQ   
```sudo apt-get install jq```

## npm install gulp
npm install gulp -g

## Install Hyperledger Fabric

Download and install the binaries - make sure they are compatible:
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;curl -sSL &lt;a href=&#34;https://goo.gl/6wtTN5&#34;&gt;https://goo.gl/6wtTN5&lt;/a&gt; | bash -s 1.0.0&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;Alternatively, you can download just the binaries that are necessary:

Hyperledger Fabric is hosted in a docker hub: https://hub.docker.com/u/hyperledger/
Since there are not necessarily “latest” versions, you may want to find the actual latest tags and pull them.
Individually you can pull them like: docker pull hyperledger/fabric-peer:latest
Pull up docker images for required components: (may have to use sudo)

&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;TAG=x86_64-1.0.6
for IMAGE in orderer couchdb peer ca tools
do
  docker pull hyperledger/fabric-${IMAGE}:${TAG} &amp;amp;&amp;amp; &lt;br /&gt;
  docker tag hyperledger/fabric-${IMAGE}:${TAG} hyperledger/fabric-${IMAGE}:latest
done&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;TAG=x86_64-0.4.6
for IMAGE in baseimage
do
    docker pull hyperledger/fabric-${IMAGE}:$[TAG] &amp;amp;&amp;amp; &lt;br /&gt;
    docker tag hyperledger/fabric-${IMAGE}:${TAG}
    hyperledger/fabric-${IMAGE}:latest
done&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;Individually and for additional requirements:

```docker pull hyperledger/fabric-peer:x86_64-1.0.6
docker pull hyperledger/fabric-ca:x86_64-1.0.6
docker pull hyperledger/fabric-orderer:x86_64-1.0.6
docker pull hyperledger/fabric-couchdb:x86_64-1.0.6
docker pull hyperledger/fabric-baseimage:x86_64-0.4.6
docker pull hyperledger/fabric-tools:x86_64-1.0.6
docker pull hyperledger/fabric-membersrvc:latest
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You will need to tag the images with &amp;ldquo;latest&amp;rdquo; - a sample is below:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;docker pull hyperledger/fabric-baseimage:x86_64-0.4.6
docker tag \
hyperledger/fabric-baseimage:x86_64-0.4.6 \
hyperledger/fabric-baseimage:latest
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Add the binaries to your .profile path&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;export PATH=$PWD/bin:$PATH
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Worryingly, some people seem to believe that the latest tag will be automatically updated — that if I pull an image marked latest, docker will take care of checking it is still the newest version before running it each time. This is emphatically not the case – just as with every other tag, you still need to manually docker pull new versions.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;launch-fabric-with-3-peers&#34;&gt;Launch Fabric with 3 peers&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://hyperledger-fabric.readthedocs.io/en/latest/write_first_app.html&#34;&gt;https://hyperledger-fabric.readthedocs.io/en/latest/write_first_app.html&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;npm install&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;./startFabric.sh&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;mkdir /fabric
cd /fabric
sudo touch docker-compose.yml
sudo nano docker-compose.yml&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;vp0:
#  container_name: vp0
  image: hyperledger/fabric-peer
  ports:
    - &amp;quot;7050:7050&amp;quot;
    - &amp;quot;7051:7051&amp;quot;
    - &amp;quot;7052:7052&amp;quot;
  environment:
  - CORE_PEER_ADDRESSAUTODETECT=true
  - CORE_VM_ENDPOINT=unix:///var/run/docker.sock
  - CORE_LOGGING_LEVEL=WARN
  - CORE_PEER_ID=vp0
  - CORE_PEER_VALIDATOR_CONSENSUS_PLUGIN=noops
  volumes:
    - /var/run/docker.sock:/var/run/docker.sock
  command: peer node start
vp1:
#  container_name: vp1
  image: hyperledger/fabric-peer
  environment:
  - CORE_PEER_ADDRESSAUTODETECT=true
  - CORE_VM_ENDPOINT=unix:///var/run/docker.sock
  - CORE_LOGGING_LEVEL=WARN
  - CORE_PEER_ID=vp1
  - CORE_PEER_DISCOVERY_ROOTNODE=vp0:7051
  - CORE_PEER_VALIDATOR_CONSENSUS_PLUGIN=noops
  volumes:
    - /var/run/docker.sock:/var/run/docker.sock
  command: peer node start
  links:
  - vp0
vp2:
#  container_name: vp2
  image: hyperledger/fabric-peer
  environment:
  - CORE_PEER_ADDRESSAUTODETECT=true
  - CORE_VM_ENDPOINT=unix:///var/run/docker.sock
  - CORE_LOGGING_LEVEL=WARN
  - CORE_PEER_ID=vp2
  - CORE_PEER_DISCOVERY_ROOTNODE=vp0:7051
  - CORE_PEER_VALIDATOR_CONSENSUS_PLUGIN=noops
  volumes:
    - /var/run/docker.sock:/var/run/docker.sock
  command: peer node start
  links:
  - vp0
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Then get set the network up with docker-compose&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;docker-compose up

docker ps

&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;let it run and check the name for vp0  - it may not be simply vp0&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;curl http://$(docker inspect --format &#39;{{ .NetworkSettings.IPAddress }}&#39; fabric_vp0_1):7050-7052-7050-7052/tcp
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Helpful docker commands&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;docker stop $(docker ps -a -q)
docker rm $(docker ps -a -q)
 &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.competa.com/blog/how-to-run-npm-without-sudo/&#34;&gt;If issues with sudo npm&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;sudo apt-get install -y nginx


gcloud compute ssh talent-exchange \
    --project redcell-191816 \
    --zone us-east1-c \
    -- -L 2200:localhost:8080


docker run \
--rm \
--interactive \
--tty \
--publish=3001:3001 \
--net=host \
node /bin/bash
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://blockchain.infinite-blue.com/wp-content/uploads/Fabric-to-Marbles-Lab-Alex-Kim_revised-0516.pdf&#34;&gt;http://blockchain.infinite-blue.com/wp-content/uploads/Fabric-to-Marbles-Lab-Alex-Kim_revised-0516.pdf&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;set-up-apache-web-server&#34;&gt;Set up Apache Web server&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;sudo apt-get update &amp;amp;&amp;amp; sudo apt-get install apache2 -y

echo &#39;&amp;lt;!doctype html&amp;gt;&amp;lt;html&amp;gt;&amp;lt;body&amp;gt;&amp;lt;h1&amp;gt;Hello World!&amp;lt;/h1&amp;gt;&amp;lt;/body&amp;gt;&amp;lt;/html&amp;gt;&#39; | sudo tee /var/www/html/index.html

sudo iptables -t nat -I PREROUTING -p tcp --dport 80 -j REDIRECT --to-ports 3001
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Utilize the iptables command to point to port 3001  (or whichever port is being served by the app)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;iptables&#34;&gt;IPTABLES&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;One way is to set up an iptables forwarding rule. iptables will then bind to the desired port (80 or 443) and forward all incoming traffic to your application&amp;rsquo;s port, such as 1337.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;However, this solution requires that you persist the iptables rule so that it gets executed on system startup, because your machine will crash or reboot eventually.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Redirecting traffic from one port to another
Let&amp;rsquo;s issue the following command to redirect incoming traffic on port 80 to our Node.js app that is listening on port 1337:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;sudo iptables -A PREROUTING -t nat -i eth0 -p tcp --dport 80 -j REDIRECT --to-port 1337
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Automatically re-apply the rule on system reboot
Next, go ahead and install iptables-persistent to save the rule permanently and have it reapplied automatically when your system reboots:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;sudo apt-get install iptables-persistent
sudo /etc/init.d/iptables-persistent save 
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;That&amp;rsquo;s it. Now your Node.js app is accessible on port 80 and you should be good to go.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;## Check listening ports&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;lsof -i -P | grep LISTEN&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;/root/fabric-samples/fabcar/hfc-key-store/&lt;/p&gt;


&lt;p class=&#34;center&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;a href=&#34;http://blockchain.redcell.ai&#34; class=&#34;button __download-link&#34;&gt;Try the Demo!&lt;/a&gt;

  &amp;nbsp;
  &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/getinsomnia/insomnia/releases/v&#34;
     class=&#34;button button--no-outline&#34;
     target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;
    View on GitHub
  &lt;/a&gt;
  
&lt;/p&gt;








            </description>
        </item>
        
        <item>
            <title>Community Code of Conduct</title>
            <link>https://redcelltalent.com/code-of-conduct/</link>
            <pubDate>
                Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000
            </pubDate>
            
            <guid>https://redcelltalent.com/code-of-conduct/</guid>
            <description>
                


&lt;p&gt;Like the technical community as a whole, the Redcell community is made up of a mixture
of professionals and volunteers from all over the world, working on every aspect of the
mission – including mentorship, teaching, and connecting people.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Diversity is a huge priority, but it can also lead to communication issues and
unhappiness. To that end, we have a few ground rules that we ask people to adhere to. This
code applies equally to founders, mentors and those seeking help and guidance.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This isn’t an exhaustive list of things that you can’t do. Rather, take it in the spirit
in which it’s intended - a guide to make it easier to enrich all of us and the technical
communities in which we participate.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This code of conduct applies to all spaces managed by the Redcell project, including Slack,
the issue tracker, and any other forums created for the project which the community uses
for communication. In addition, violations of this code outside these spaces may affect
a person&amp;rsquo;s ability to participate within them.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you believe someone is violating the code of conduct, we ask that you report it by
emailing &lt;a href=&#34;mailto:contact@redcell.ai&#34;&gt;contact@redcell.ai&lt;/a&gt;. For more details
please see our Reporting Guidelines&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Be friendly and patient.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Be welcoming.&lt;/strong&gt; We strive to be a community that welcomes and supports people of all
backgrounds and identities. This includes, but is not limited to members of any race,
ethnicity, culture, national origin, colour, immigration status, social and economic
class, educational level, sex, sexual orientation, gender identity and expression, age,
size, family status, political belief, religion, and mental and physical ability.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Be considerate.&lt;/strong&gt; Your work will be used by other people, and you in turn will
depend on the work of others. Any decision you take will affect users and colleagues,
and you should take those consequences into account when making decisions. Remember
that we&amp;rsquo;re a world-wide community, so you might not be communicating in someone
else&amp;rsquo;s primary language.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Be respectful.&lt;/strong&gt; Not all of us will agree all the time, but disagreement is no
excuse for poor behavior and poor manners. We might all experience some frustration
now and then, but we cannot allow that frustration to turn into a personal attack.
It’s important to remember that a community where people feel uncomfortable or
threatened is not a productive one. Members of the Redcell community should be respectful
when dealing with other members as well as with people outside the Redcell community.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Be careful in the words that you choose.&lt;/strong&gt; We are a community of professionals,
and we conduct ourselves professionally. Be kind to others. Do not insult or put
down other participants. Harassment and other exclusionary behavior aren&amp;rsquo;t acceptable.
This includes, but is not limited to:

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Violent threats or language directed against another person.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Discriminatory jokes and language.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Posting sexually explicit or violent material.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Posting (or threatening to post) other people&amp;rsquo;s personally identifying information (&amp;ldquo;doxing&amp;rdquo;).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Personal insults, especially those using racist or sexist terms.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Unwelcome sexual attention.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Advocating for, or encouraging, any of the above behavior.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Repeated harassment of others. In general, if someone asks you to stop, then stop.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;When we disagree, try to understand why.&lt;/strong&gt; Disagreements, both social and technical,
happen all the time and Redcell is no exception. It is important that we resolve
disagreements and differing views constructively. Remember that we’re different. The
strength of Redcell comes from its varied community, people from a wide range of backgrounds.
Different people have different perspectives on issues. Being unable to understand why
someone holds a viewpoint doesn’t mean that they’re wrong. Don’t forget that it is human
to err and blaming each other doesn’t get us anywhere. Instead, focus on helping to resolve
issues and learning from mistakes.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Original text courtesy of the
&lt;a href=&#34;http://web.archive.org/web/20141109123859/http://speakup.io/coc.html&#34;&gt;Speak Up! project&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;questions&#34;&gt;Questions?&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Please send all questions or concerns to &lt;a href=&#34;mailto:contact@redcell.ai&#34;&gt;contact@redcell.ai&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;


&lt;p class=&#34;center&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;a href=&#34;http://blockchain.redcell.ai&#34; class=&#34;button __download-link&#34;&gt;Try the Demo!&lt;/a&gt;

  &amp;nbsp;
  &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/getinsomnia/insomnia/releases/vcode-of-conduct&#34;
     class=&#34;button button--no-outline&#34;
     target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;
    View on GitHub
  &lt;/a&gt;
  
&lt;/p&gt;








            </description>
        </item>
        
    </channel>
</rss>
