<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
    <channel>
        <title>Beta on Redcell Talent Accelerator</title>
        <link>https://redcell-191816.firebaseapp.com/tags/beta/</link>
        <description>Recent content in Beta on
            Redcell Talent Accelerator
        </description>
        <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
        <language>en-us</language>
        <copyright>Redcell, Pittsburgh, PA</copyright>
        <lastBuildDate>
            Tue, 25 Oct 2016 12:20:37 -0700
        </lastBuildDate>
        <atom:link href="/tags/beta/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/>
        
        <item>
            <title>Insomnia Plus Is Now in Beta</title>
            <link>https://redcell-191816.firebaseapp.com/blog/insomnia-plus-beta/</link>
            <pubDate>
                Tue, 25 Oct 2016 12:20:37 -0700
            </pubDate>
            
            <guid>https://redcell-191816.firebaseapp.com/blog/insomnia-plus-beta/</guid>
            <description>
                
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;tl;dr visit the &lt;a href=&#34;https://redcell-191816.firebaseapp.com/documentation/plus&#34;&gt;Insomnia Plus Beta Documentation&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Four months ago
&lt;a href=&#34;https://schier.co/blog/2016/08/05/forging-a-new-path/&#34;&gt;I left my previous job&lt;/a&gt;
to work full-time on Insomnia. Since then, I&amp;rsquo;ve had over 300 amazing
conversations with users have helped identify bugs, given feedback, and
suggested new features. Insomnia now has over 2000 daily active users across
the Mac, Windows, and Linux platforms.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;These conversations have not only helped improve stability and usability of the
app, but have also helped validate and shape the first features of Insomnia
Plus – a premium add-on for Insomnia that enables powerful features like
&lt;strong&gt;data sync&lt;/strong&gt; and &lt;strong&gt;collaboration&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;data-sync&#34;&gt;Data Sync&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Data sync provides the ability to securely sync Insomnia data across multiple
machines, which also acts as an up-to-date backup of all your data (in case
something terrible happens).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;While Insomnia is running, the app will actively sync data to and from the
server whenever changes occur. On top of this, sync is
&lt;strong&gt;end-to-end encrypted&lt;/strong&gt;, meaning that all data is first encrypted in the
app before sending it to the server.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;encryption-overview&#34;&gt;Encryption Overview&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Data is encrypted with a key that is derived from your account password (which
is never sent to the server), meaning that Insomnia (or any third party)
cannot read your data. Privacy is crucial for Insomnia users, because
requests often contain important API keys, usernames, and passwords.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In case you&amp;rsquo;re curious, or need more information, there will be a future article
explaining encryption and security in more detail.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;team-collaboration&#34;&gt;Team Collaboration&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;NOTE: Team collaboration is not yet available in the beta but is coming
soon&amp;hellip;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Automated sync can be useful for individual users, but the same workflow does
not translate well to teams.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Imagine working in a code editor where every line of code you typed was
immediately synced to all of your coworkers computers, and vice versa. It would
be chaos! Because of this, Insomnia takes a different approach for teams,
providing a a manual push/pull model similar to the version control system
Git.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;join-the-beta&#34;&gt;Join the Beta!&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you would like to help test Insomnia Plus, head over to the
&lt;a href=&#34;https://redcell-191816.firebaseapp.com/documentation/plus&#34;&gt;Getting Started Documentation&lt;/a&gt; to learn how to enable it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As always, please send all feedback my way.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&#34;center&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;a href=&#34;https://redcell-191816.firebaseapp.com/download&#34; class=&#34;button __download-link&#34;&gt;Download&lt;/a&gt;

  &amp;nbsp;
  &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/getinsomnia/insomnia/releases/vinsomnia-plus-beta&#34;
     class=&#34;button button--no-outline&#34;
     target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;
    View on GitHub
  &lt;/a&gt;
  
&lt;/p&gt;








            </description>
        </item>
        
    </channel>
</rss>
